机密档案 82-712
File 82-712.
迪瑞克警官正在进行询问
Agent Rick Dicker interrogating.
请说出你的姓名
State your name, please.
呃 托尼 托尼·莱丁格
Uh, Tony. Tony Rydinger.
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me about the incident.
就是 有一个女孩 他是我们班的
Well, there's this girl, um, in my class.
我在运动会上看到她
I saw her at the track meet.
- 你是巴小倩对吧 - 是的 没错
- You're, uh, Violet, right? - That's me.
我以前也认识她 可她变了
I sort of knew her, but she'd changed.
好像更放松也更自信
Relaxed. She was more sure of herself.
很酷 很可爱
Cool, cute.
然后我就约她去看电影
I asked her out to a movie.
那就周五见
So, Friday?
- 周五见 - 周五见
- Friday. - Friday.
然后我就去看运动会了
And I went to watch the track meet.
再后来 停车场里就出事了
Not long after, this thing happened in the parking lot.
我就是 暗中破坏王
Behold! The Underminer!
我一直在地下活动 我是破坏之王
I am always beneath you, but nothing is beneath me!
可事情更奇怪了
As if things aren't weird enough,
我还从车底下看到了几个怪人
I look over and I see these boots.
你们两个待在这
You two, stay here.
等一下 真的要上吗
Wait. Should we be doing this?
用超能力还是违法的
It is still illegal.
他们好像是超人
They looked like superheroes.
- 再不上就跟丢了 - 那好吧
- We're gonna lose him. - Oh, all right.
你一个人控制现场
One of you patrol the perimeter,
保证周围市民的安全
keep the crowds back and safe.
另一个 照顾好小杰
The other, watch after Jack-Jack.
我以为我们也要去战斗
But I thought we were gonna go with...
能帮我个忙吗
You heard your mother.
快送我上去
Trampoline me.
我去控制现场了
I call perimeter!
哪也不许去
You're not going anywhere,
你这小捣蛋鬼
you little maggoty creep!
我看准时机想赶快逃跑
I see my chance to get out of there.
可是 有一个女孩的声音听着有些耳熟
But there's something familiar about one of the kids' voices.
就是那个女孩
The girl, she's upset
她一生气就把面具给摘了
and she throws down her mask...
竟然是她
and it's her!
噢 托尼
Oh. Tony!
嗨
Hi.
呃 我好像不是你想的那样
Uh, this isn't what you think it is.
这太奇怪了
It was just getting too freaky.
我一下接受不了 就跑了
I couldn't handle it and ran off.
我觉得有点对不起她
I feel kinda bad about it.
也许我应该跟她打声招呼什么的
Maybe I should've said "hi" or something?
超人不合法也不是她的错
It's not her fault superheroes are illegal.
我也不是不喜欢厉害的女孩
And it's not like I don't like strong girls.
其实我对我自己很有 信心
I'm pretty secure manhood-wise.
那是什么
What is that?
你和别人说起这件事吗 比如你父母
Have you told anyone else about this? Your parents?
没有 他们肯定以为我在撒谎
No, they'd only think I was hiding something.
- 您能明白吗 - 很明白 孩子
- You know what I mean? - Sure, kid.
我很喜欢这个女孩 迪瑞克先生
I like this girl, Mr. Dicker.
我本来周五晚上要和她出去约会的
I'm supposed to go out with her Friday night.
可惜那只能成为遗憾了
Now, things are just gonna be weird.
我真希望能忘掉那天看见的东西
I wish I could forget I ever saw her in that suit.
你会忘掉的
You will, kid.
我保证
You will.
《超人总动员2》
我的天
Come on!
黑暗之外的一切都破坏吧
Consider yourself undermined!
- 暗中破坏王 - 我们又见面了
- Underminer! - We meet again... Huh?
我去 现在还得费事处理掉他了
Oh, great! Now, he's on the agenda.
超能先生
Incredible!
让你尝尝我的厉害
Meet Jack Hammer!
再见
Buh-bye!
不不不
No, no, no! No, no, no!
所有人往后退 往后退
Everybody, stay back! Okay? Stay back!
又想让我带孩子 自己逞英雄
You're not sticking me with babysitting!
钻头失控了 停不下来 暗中破坏王那家伙跑掉了
I can't steer it or stop it. And the Underminer's escaped!
我们必须让它停下 鲍勃 列车来了
We'll have to stop it... Bob! The monorail!
是酷冰侠 耶
Frozone! Yeah!
得让列车停下
We have to stop this thing
不能让他破坏钢架桥
before it gets to the overpass!
我尽量让它远离建筑物
I'll try to keep it away from the buildings!
哎 小心
Hey, lady!
真是太谢谢你了 年轻人
Thank you so much, young man!
什么
What?
巴小倩
Violet!
停车
Stop!
让他们停下
Everybody, stop!
- 爸爸小心 - 小飞
- Heads up, Dad! - Dash!
小倩 你怎么不看着小杰
Violet! Who's watching Jack-Jack?
小飞在照看他呢
Dash is watching him!
小倩 你抱着他
Violet, here, you take him!
它冲着市中心去了
It's headed for City Hall!
快去帮妈妈
Mom needs help!
超人又现身了 这是我们的好机会
They're out in public again! This is our chance!
跟上他们 跟上酷冰侠
Follow them, follow Frozone!
鲍勃 帮我搞定那个锅炉
Bob! Help me with the boiler!
这样就没问题了
That should do it!
你们在这干什么 还不赶快出去
What are you kids doing? Get out of here!
马上就要爆炸了
This thing's gonna blow!
来不及了
There's no time!
我们成功了
We did it!
不许动 超人们
Freeze, Supers!
噢 我们又怎么了
Oh, what did we do?
打扰一下 您是 酷冰侠
Excuse me, Mr. Zone?
不好意思 我出现在这违法了
Sorry, but I'm not really supposed to be here.
这太不公平了
Which seems wrong...
你说呢
doesn't it?
也许你有这个兴趣 改变法律
Perhaps you'd be interested in changing that law?
几位超人 包括酷冰侠
Superheroes including Frozone,
超能先生 和弹力女超人
Mr. Incredible, and Elastigirl...
对城市建筑造成很大破坏
caused further damage to the city.
暗中破坏王仍然逍遥法外
The Underminer remains at large.
先动手的又不是我们
We didn't start this fight.
你们也没有阻止他啊
Well, you didn't finish it either!
你们阻止暗中破坏王破坏城市了吗
Did you stop the Underminer from inflicting more damage?
没有
No.
你们成功阻止他们抢银行了吗
Did you stop him from robbing the banks?
- 没有 - 你们抓住他了吗
- No. - Did you catch him?
- 没有 - 银行都有保险
- No. - The banks were insured.
那突发情况我们也有
We have infrastructure in place
相应的基础措施进行应对
to deal with these matters.
要是这次你们没有乱插手
If you had simply done nothing...
一切都会顺畅无阻的解决
everything would now be
不会有麻烦的
proceeding in an orderly fashion.
难道你想让我们什么都不做吗
You'd have preferred we do nothing?
最好袖手旁观
Without a doubt.
你也不帮我说话
You weren't much help.
你们不想别人坑
Do you want out of the hole?
就别自己先往坑里跳
First you gotta put down the shovel.
这算哪门子事啊
Well, that went poorly.
爸爸 我知道你今天不开心
Dad, this is probably
我不该给你添堵
not the best time to tell you about this...
不过 今天还有一件别的事 有个同学
but something else happened today with a kid...
看到了我摘了面具
and my mask.
噢 对了 迪瑞克
Oh, hey, Rick.
小倩的一个朋友 一个叫托尼的孩子
Violet thinks a friend of hers, a kid named Tony...
可能看到她是超人了 当时她没带面具
might have seen her in the outfit, without her mask.
- 他是大嘴巴么 - 不知道
- Talkative type? - Don't know.
我只知道他姓莱丁格
Last name is Rydinger.
托尼·莱丁格
Tony Rydinger.
我去找找
I'll check it out.
鲍勃 何莉
Bob, Helen...
我还有句话要说
a word if you don't mind.
超人援助项目遭到中止了
Uh, the program's been shut down.
什么
What?
那些政客永远不能理解
Politicians don't understand people...
有人做好事只是因为他们想伸张正义
who do good simply because it's right.
搞得那些政客很紧张
It makes 'em nervous.
多年来他们一直想抓超人的把柄
They've been gunning for Supers for years.
今天让他们抓了个正着
Today was all they needed.
总而言之
Anyway...
我要走人了
I'm done.
我只能在帮你们再多交
I'm afraid two more weeks in the motel
两个星期的汽车旅馆住宿费
is the best I can do for ya.
帮不上太多了
It ain't much.
你为我们做的够多了
You've done plenty, Rick.
我们不会忘记的
We won't forget.
很荣幸能和你们这样
Well, it has been a great honor
善良的人一起工作
working with you good people.
谢谢你做的一切 祝你好运
Thanks for everything, and good luck.
谢谢你也是
Yeah. You, too.
你刚才洗手了吗
Did you wash your hands?
应该用肥皂洗
With soap?
你擦手了吗
Did you dry them?
什么 里面怎么都是难吃的蔬菜 哪个讨厌鬼点这么多菜
What? Is this all vegetables? Who ordered all vegetables?
我点的 多吃蔬菜有好处
I did. They're good and you're going to have some.
我们难道就不提这事了
Are we going to talk about it?
- 什么事 - 大家都装看不见的事
- What? - The elephant in the room.
- 什么看不见的事 - 那我还是不要提了
- What elephant? - I guess not then.
你指的是今天的事
You're referring to today.
对 今天到底是什么情况
Yeah, what's the deal with today?
我们都会犯错误
We all made mistakes.
举个例子来说
For example,
你们两个今天应该照顾小杰
you kids were supposed to watch Jack-Jack.
那我们去看孩子 你们俩打击犯罪拯救城市
Babysitting, while you guys did the important stuff.
我们已经谈过了
We talked about this.
你们年纪太小还不能做决定
You're not old enough to decide about these things.
可我们多少能帮上点忙
We are old enough to help out.
对
Yeah!
这不是你说的吗 爸爸
Isn't that what you tell us, Dad?
对 这个 帮忙也可以有很多种形式
Yeah, well, "help out" can mean many different things.
你们有麻烦我们就应该帮忙
But we're supposed to help, if there's trouble.
- 对 也对 - 你们难道...
- Well, yeah, but... - Aren't you
- 不为我们今天帮忙而高兴吗 - 我很高兴 但是
- glad we helped today? - Yeah, I know but...
你说过为我们感到骄傲
You said that you were proud of us.
我是说了是骄傲
Well, yeah, I was. Am!
我们也要去教训坏蛋
We wanna fight bad guys!
不 你们不许去
No, you don't!
你说过情况已经不一样了
You said things were different now.
的确不一样 那可是在岛上
And they were, on the island.
我可没有说你们现在…
But I didn't mean that from now on...
所以我们以后永远不能使用超能力
So now, we've gotta go back to never using our powers.
这会影响我的人生观
It defines who I am.
我们没说你们不能…
We're not saying you have...
- 什么 - 电视里就是这么说的
- What? - Someone on TV said it.
能不能先吃饭 先别吵
Can we just eat?
饭都快凉了
The dinner, while it's hot?
我们今天做错事了吗
Did we do something wrong?
- 是的 - 没有
- Yes. - No.
我们今天做的不是错事
We didn't do anything wrong.
使用超能力还是违法的
Superheroes are illegal.
不管公不公平 这就是法律
Whether it's fair or not, that's the law.
法律就应该公平 不然我们怎么教育孩子
The law should be fair. What are we teaching our kids?
叫他们怎么尊重法律
To respect the law!
要是那法律是不公平的 不值得尊重的 怎么办
Even when the law is disrespectful?
法律不公平也通过法律来修正
If laws are unjust, there are laws to change them!
不然一切都乱套了
Otherwise, it's chaos!
我们生活就已经乱套了
Which is exactly what we have!
我是觉得 只有那样才酷
I just thought it was kinda cool.
- 哪样才酷 - 与家人一起 去打击犯罪
- What was? - Fighting crime as a family.
那是很酷
It was cool.
但也过去了 世界就是这样
But it's over. The world is what it is.
我们必需要适应世界
We have to adapt.
世界是不是很糟
Are things bad?
世界很正常
Things are fine.
我能走了吗
May I be excused?
我们还要在汽车旅馆住到什么时候呀爸爸
How much longer in the motel, Dad?
- 呃... - 不会太久了宝贝
- Uh... - Not much longer, honey.
以后该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我也不知道
I don't know.
也许迪瑞克还会帮我
Maybe Dicker will find something?
他不会再帮我们了
Dicker is done, Bob.
我们想要再一次成为超人 根本就是幻想
Any thought we had about being Supers again is fantasy.
我们中至少得有一个人找份工作
One of us has gotta get a job.
找份工作
One of us?
你在安心保险干了很多年
You did a long stint at Insuricare.
每一分钟都会是煎熬
Hated every minute of it.
我知道这样你很痛苦
I know it was hard on you.
也许我去找份工作
Maybe it's my turn in the private sector
你留在家里照顾孩子们
and you take care of the kids...
不 还是我去吧 我必须要工作
No, I'm doing this. I need to do this.
我的西服和领带你放哪了
You know where my suit and ties are?
飞机砸中了我们房子的时候
Burned up when...
都烧了
The jet destroyed our house.
是啊
Yeah.
我们现在不能依靠任何人的帮助
We can't count on anyone else now, Bob.
只能靠自己
It's just us.
不能等着别人
We can't wait for...
没有人护着咱们了
No lifeguard on duty!
得自力更生咯
Swim at your own risk.
你今天又跑哪去了
Oh, where'd you go today?
为什么不跟我们去喝茶
I noticed you missed all the fun.
别生气 因为我知道什么是优雅退场
Don't be mad because I know when to leave a party.
因为我和你们一样违反了法律
I'm just as illegal as you guys.
另外 我还知道警察会放了你们
Besides, I knew the cops would let you go.
对 鲍勃还想多住两天
Yeah, in spite of Bob's best efforts.
是 没错
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我听说援助项目停了
I heard the program shut down.
你们在旅馆里还能住多久
How much longer are you in this motel?
两个星期
Two weeks.
对了 你说了我可以帮你们
Now, you know the offer still stands.
谢谢你的好意 可我们家有五口人
You're very generous, but there are five of us.
不能跑去给你们添麻烦
We wouldn't do that to you and Honey.
好吧 随时欢迎
Well, door's always open.
不过今天不光只有坏消息
You know, the news isn't all bad.
你们在警察局里喝茶的时候
While you guys were being detained...
有个人来找我 他可是大财团的代表
I was approached by a dude who represents this tycoon.
- 文斯顿·迪沃 - 他想找我谈谈
- Winston Deavor. - Wants to talk...
还有你们两个 谈谈超能力的事
with me, with you two, about hero stuff.
我查过了
I checked him out.
他很守法
He's legit.
是迪瑞克的学生 他想见我们
Trained under Dicker. He wants to meet.
噢 天哪 又是超能力惹来的麻烦
Ah, jeez! More superhero trouble.
我们今天刚从警察局里出来鲁修斯
We just came from the police station, Lucius.
- 什么时候去 - 今天晚上 我现在就过去
- When? - Tonight. I'm going there now.
祝你一路顺风 我们就不去了
You enjoy, I'm sitting this one out.
他想叫我们三个一起去
He wants all three of us.
亲爱的 我们起码先去听听他要说些什么
Honey, let's just at least hear what he has to say.
地址在名片上 我们一会见
You got the address, I'll meet you guys there.
我们还得穿超能装去
Go in our Supersuits?
对
Yeah.
也许还是穿旧式超能装比较好
Might wanna wear the old Supersuits.
我感觉那个人挺怀旧的
Got a feeling he's nostalgic.
你们两个要去哪
Where are you going?
今天晚上外面的空气特别的新鲜
The fresh air is especially good tonight.
要是小杰醒了
If Jack-Jack wakes up...
你知道该怎么办
I know the drill.
这是你们的识别牌 请走这边
Your security badges. Please, this way.
噢 对了 我是您的头号粉丝
Hey, listen, you're my biggest fan.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
真的 我是您的头号粉丝
I'm your biggest fan. Shoot!
我 最爱超级英雄
I love superheroes!
强大的超能力 超能装
The powers, the costumes...
还有华丽的战斗
the mythic struggles.
我是文斯顿·迪沃 可以叫我阿文
Winston Deavor. You can call me Win.
非常高兴能见到各位
Genuine pleasure to meet you.
- 酷冰侠 - 我也很高兴见到你
- Frozone! - It's good to see you.
- 弹力女超人 - 见到你很高兴
- Elastigirl. - Nice to meet you.
- 还有超能先生 - 你好
- Mr. Incredible! - Hello.
∮ 超能先生 ∮
∮ Incredible ∮
∮ 把坏人抓住 砰 ∮
∮ Catching the bad guys Pow, pow, pow ∮
∮ 酷冰侠 ∮
∮ Frozone ∮
我简直无法用言语表达我内心的兴奋 这位是
Can't tell you what a thrill this is. And this...
大家好各位超人们 真的非常抱歉我迟到了
Oh, hello there, superheroes. I'm so sorry I'm late.
这是我拖拖拉拉的妹妹 伊芙琳
...is my tardy sister, Evelyn.
我的确拖拉 我先自责 你不用这么指责我好吗 文斯顿
And I'm scolding myself so you don't have to, Winston!
太好了
Spectacular.
我父亲一定非常自豪
My father was so proud
我能和各位超人有一星半点的联系
that I was even remotely connected to you guys.
他管你们叫 正义的最后一道防线
He used to call you the last line of defense.
他最支持超能力了
He was your top supporter.
他出钱支持超人事业
He donated to superhero causes.
还筹资
He raised money
修建了市中心公园的傲魄侠雕像
for the Dynaguy statue in Avery Park.
他认识不少超人
He got to know many Supers personally.
甚至家里还安装了电话
Even installed a phone
紧急情况下
with direct lines to Gazerbeam and Fironic...
能直接打给电光眼和长枪侠
in case of emergencies.
他可高兴了 天天对人炫耀
He loved that, showed it off to everyone.
你们被迫停止活动的时候
He was heartbroken
他真的很伤心
when you were all forced to go underground.
父亲相信世界
Father believed the world
如果少了超人的保护会更危险
would become more dangerous without you.
没想到他的话成真了
He didn't know how right he was.
家里进了贼
There was a break-in.
我父亲马上打电话
My father called Gazerbeam.
直接向电光眼求助
The direct line.
没有人接
No answer.
他又打给长枪侠 也没有人接
He called Fironic, no answer.
当时刚刚宣布禁止使用超能力
Superheroes had just been made illegal...
父亲就在电话旁边被强盗
The robbers discovered him on the phone...
开枪杀害了
and shot him.
所以
So...
你们一定很难过
It must've been hard.
母亲尤其难过
Especially for Mother.
几个月后母亲伤心过度 也过世了
She died a few months later. Heartbreak.
如果超人没有被迫隐藏身份
If superheroes had not been forced underground...
也许父亲也不会被杀
it never would've happened.
或者父亲可以一听到强盗进屋
Or Dad could've taken Mom to the safe room
就带着妈妈躲进安全屋
as soon as he knew there was trouble.
我绝对不能同意这种说法
I disagree strongly!
不过现在还是不要讨论这个问题了
But we're not going into it right now.
重点是当时没人相信
The point is...
我们会顺利接手
nobody expected us
继续经营父亲的公司
to be able to actually run Dad's company.
不过 伊芙琳是设计师 我又擅长经商
But with Evelyn as designer, and myself as operator...
我们夜以继日的工作 迪沃科技才不断发展
uh, we threw ourselves into building DEVTECH
有了今天的成就
into what it is today.
我们是世界上数一数二的大型电信公司
A world-class telecommunications company.
规模非常大
Bigger than ever.
大企业就更要负起责任 支持正义的事业
Perfectly positioned to make some wrong things right.
所以我们见面了
Hence, this meeting.
我先问一个问题
Let me ask you something.
说说你们被迫停止活动的
What is the main reason
真正原因是什么
you were all forced underground?
- 因为人们的无知 - 其实是印象
- Ignorance. - Perception.
就拿暗中破坏王的事来说
Take today for example, with the Underminer.
情况非常危急
Difficult situation.
你们需要迅速做出许多艰难的决定
You were faced with a lot of hard decisions.
没错 继续说
Oh, tell me about it.
可我不知道这个过程
I can't.
因为我并没有亲眼看到
Because I didn't see it...
其他人也看不到
neither did anyone else.
所以 你们今天奋力和坏人搏斗的时候
So, when you fight bad guys like today...
人们既看不到战斗也不知道前因后果
people don't see the fight or what led up to it.
他们只能看到政客想让他们看到的
They see what politicians tell them to see.
他们看到了破坏 又看到了你们
They see destruction and they see you.
那么 如果我们想
So, if we wanna change
彻底改变公众的对超级英雄过时的印象
people's perceptions about superheroes...
就需要
we need you
你们与世界分享你们独有的超级视角
to share your perceptions with the world.
- 具体应该怎么做呢 - 用镜头
- How do we do that? - With cameras.
我们要把超人的视角分享给全世界
We need you to share your perceptions with the world.
那我们要怎么做
How do we do that?
我们会在你们穿的超能装里面
We embed tiny cameras, like those,
安装微型摄像头
into your Supersuits.
哇哦 真小巧
Wow, so small.
可是画质非常好
And the picture is outstanding.
谢谢 是我亲自设计的
Thanks! Designed 'em myself.
我们有资源 有活动家
We've got resources, lobbyists,
在全世界都有非常广泛的人脉
worldwide connections...
还有最重要的 就是保险
and very important, insurance.
保险才是关键
Insurance is key.
现在缺的就是最厉害的超人了
All we need now are the super-est superheroes.
也就是你们三位 来吧
It needs you three. Come on!
加入我们 努力让超能力再次合法
Help me make all Supers legal again.
这真是太棒了
This sounds great!
马上就开始吧 我的任务是什么
Let's get this going. What's my first assignment?
超能先生 你这种热情非常好
That enthusiasm is golden.
请保持住 其实我们要想改变超人形象
Now hold on to it. But for our first move...
重点在弹力女超人身上
Well, Elastigirl is our best play.
难道 她比我更强
Better than me?
我是说 她很好
I mean, she's good.
她真的很有能力 可是
Really, a credit to her...
你懂得 你懂我意思
You know. You know.
我很尊重您
With great respect...
不过您还是不要太依赖
let's not test the whole
保险反正都可以理赔 这种想法
"insurance-will-pay- for-everything" idea...
特别是一开始的时候好吗
on the first go 'round, okay?
等一下 你是什么意思 我能力不太行么
Wait a minute. You're saying what? I'm messy?
是这样 伊芙琳作了成本收益分析
Well, Evelyn did a cost-benefit analysis...
比较了你们停止活动之前五年间
comparing all your last five years of crime fighting
你们打击犯罪情况的数据
before going underground.
弹力女超人的数据是最好的
And Elastigirl's numbers are self-explanatory.
这种比较根本就不公平
Well, it's not a fair comparison!
听着 重要的问题就得用重量级的解决办法
Heavyweight problems need heavyweight solutions.
说的对 最终所有的问题
Of course! We're gonna solve
我们都要解决
all kinds of problems together.
不过 在此之前要来一次完美的公关 重点推出弹力女超人
After the perfect launch with Elastigirl!
那么 你怎么想
So, what do you say?
你问我怎么想
What do I say?
我 不知道
I don't know.
你怎么可能不知道
What do you mean, you don't know?
几个小时前 你还说超能力的时代已经过去了
A few hours ago, you were saying it was over...
当超人只是幻想
and being a superhero was a fantasy.
可现在改变人生的好机会来了
Now, you get the offer of a lifetime
你居然说你不知道
and you don't know?
没那么简单 鲍勃 我还要考虑保护孩子们
It's not that simple, Bob. I wanna protect the kids!
我也在考虑孩子
So do I.
违法是会坐牢的 鲍勃
From jail, Bob!
干什么才能不违法
And how do you do that?
现在明明有改变法律的机会
By turning down a chance to change the law
让孩子们以后不用再隐藏能力
that forces them to hide what they are?
他们自己还不知道自己要什么 他们还只是孩子
They haven't decided what they are. They're still kids.
他们是有超能力的孩子 也就是超人
Kids with powers, which makes them Supers...
不管以后他们决定用不用超能力
whether they decide to use those powers or not.
这样都对他们有好处
This will benefit them.
我现在最应该陪着他们
It's not a good time to be away.
小飞连作业都做不好
Dash is having trouble with homework...
小倩成天想着约会的事
Vi is worried about her first date
就是和那个她喜欢的男孩子 叫托尼的
with that boy she likes, Tony...
然后小杰又
and Jack-Jack...
小杰 小杰怎么了
Jack-Jack? What's wrong with him?
好吧 小杰没有任何问题
Okay, nothing's wrong with Jack-Jack.
不过就是普通孩子也需要很多关心的
But even a normal baby needs a lot of attention.
我总感觉不该离开家
I'm just not sure I can leave.
你怎么不能离开家
Of course you can leave.
你一定要去 只要我..
You've got to. So that I...
我们就可以重新正大光明的当超人
we can be Supers again,
我们的孩子才能选择未来啊
so our kids can have that choice.
你是说你的未来吧
So you can have that choice.
说的对 是的
All right, yes!
说的是我的未来
So I can have that choice.
而且让我上 我一定能做的非常好
And I would do a great job!
不管文斯顿那个倒霉数据说的是什么
Regardless of what Deavor's pie charts say or whatever...
不过 他们要的是你
But they want you.
你也 一定会像我
And you'll do a great...
一样
job...
出色
too.
看你这样连我都跟着着难受
Well, that was excruciating to watch.
我不能对你撒谎
I can't lie to you.
我被选上了很开心 更要飘飘然了 可是
It's nice to be wanted. Flattering, you know, but...
你想怎么选
But what's the choice?
第一 好好工作拿到报酬
One, do this right,
我们就能搬出汽车旅馆
get well paid, we're out of the motel...
超能力合法化对超人们
and things get better for all Supers,
对孩子们也有好处
including our kids.
第二种
Or two...
我们要在两周内找到工作 要不然我们就只能流落街头
I find a job in two weeks or we're homeless.
你知道这有多疯狂么
You know it's crazy, right?
为了家人 我得离开家
To help my family, I gotta leave it.
要改变法律 得先违法
To fix the law, I gotta break it.
你会做的很棒的
You'll be great.
这我也知道
I know I will.
可你怎么办 还有孩子要照顾
But what about you? We have kids.
我会看孩子 没问题
I'll watch the kids, no problem.
- 很简单 - 很简单啊
- Easy. - Easy, huh?
你可真可爱
You're adorable.
反正如果真的有问题
Well, if there is a problem,
我就随时赶过来好了
I'll drop this thing and come right back.
完全没必要
You won't need to.
我来搞定 你尽管去工作是了
I got it, you go do this thing.
认真工作
Do it so...
虽然我做得更好
I can do it better.
我是文斯顿
Deavor here.
我是弹力女超人
This is Elastigirl.
我同意了
I'm in.
文斯顿先生 真的谢谢你
Mr. Deavor, it's wonderful...
可是这也太破费了
but it's too generous.
哪里哪里 这点小事不足挂齿
Nonsense! That's the least we can do.
我们现在是合作伙伴
We're partners now!
怎么能让你们住在汽车旅馆里
Can't have my partners living in a motel.
可是这是谁的房子
But whose house? Is it a house?
是我的房子 我有好几套
It's my house. I have several.
那套平时也没人住 你们尽管住就是了
I'm not using that one. Stay as long as you need.
我都不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
我建议你说 谢谢
How about "thanks"?
这就是我们的新家
This is our new house?
好了 别太激动 是借给我们住
Okay, easy, tiger. It's being loaned to us.
这还真舒适 豪华
This is homey.
快看这地方 真棒
Look at this place.
文斯顿买下这里之前 别墅的主人
Deavor bought it from an eccentric billionaire...
是一个不喜欢暴露行踪的亿万富翁
who liked to come and go without being seen...
所以房子里有好几个秘密出口
so the house has multiple hidden exits.
真是一个不显眼的别墅
Good thing we won't stand out.
住在这 我们肯定不会再乱七八糟的人给盯上了
Wouldn't want to attract any unnecessary attention.
这个院子真大啊
It's got a big yard!
这是不是有点太夸张了
Isn't this a bit much?
旁边还有森林
Near a forest!
难道你更愿意住汽车旅馆
Would you rather be at the motel?
还有泳池
And a pool!
妈妈的新工作到底是做什么的
What exactly is Mom's new job?
重要的事我们不用在住旅馆
The important thing is we're out of the motel.
我喜欢妈妈的新工作
I like Mom's new job!
你看看别墅里还有瀑布
Well, check out the water features.
- 哦! - 哇
- Oh! - Wow.
真是太酷了
Wicked cool!
小飞别玩了
Hey! Dash! Stop it!
- 别把沙发毁了 住手 - 住手 小飞
- Not the couch! Stop it! - No! Dash!
停下
Stop!
- 别乱按按钮 - 沙发进水了
- Don't touch the buttons! - The couch!
- 小飞 - 不
- Dash! - No!
不 不
No, no!
我的天
Oh, no. Oh, boy.
这 是我吗
This isn't me.
怎么这衣服是暗黑风格的
I'm not all dark and angsty.
我是弹力女超人
I'm Elastigirl.
应该是很灵活的
I'm, you know, flexible.
是伊芙琳设计的
E designed this?
不 是个叫亚历山大·盖尔巴奇的人
No, some guy named Alexander Galbaki.
幸好是你穿不是我
Glad it's you and not me,
因为莫衣娜肯定会来找你
'cause you're gonna hear from her.
这张纸条也是给你的
This note came with it.
什么
What?
居然是新的弹力摩托车
A new Elasticycle.
弹力摩托车 我真不知道你还会骑摩托车
Elasticycle? I didn't know you had a bike.
我有段时间莫西干发型呢
Hey, I had a mohawk.
有的是你不知道的
There's a lot about me you don't know.
莫西干发型
Yeah, but... A mohawk?
啊 也没什么大不了的
Ah, you didn't miss anything.
这辆车是电动的
Oh, yeah! This one's electric.
- 什么意思 - 哇哇哇
- What's that mean? - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
就是扭矩大了点 我能驾驭的住的
Means it's torque-y. I'll get the hang of it.
你一定会很棒的
You will be great.
我当然会很棒 你也会很棒
I will be great. And you will, too.
我们俩都很棒
We will both be great.
再见 亲爱的
Bye, sweetie.
等一下
Wait a minute!
- 那是弹力女超人吗 - 我觉得那是弹力女超人
- Is that Elastigirl? - I think that's Elastigirl.
嘿 弹力女超人
Hey! Elastigirl!
我喜欢你 弹力女超人
Marry me, Elastigirl!
∮ 弹力女超人来了 ∮
∮ Here comes Elastigirl ∮
∮ 弹力弹弹弹 ∮
∮ Stretching her ∮
别唱歌了
No theme songs
要不然我就掉头回家
or I'll turn this bus right around!
看看窗外的景色
Look at that.
这里是新城
New Urbem.
想要记录下打击犯罪的大新闻
You wanna make a big crime fighting statement...
就要去犯罪率最高的地方
you go where the crime is big.
你因为犯罪率高感到兴奋这也太奇怪了 文斯顿
Strange thing to be excited about, Winston.
这里简直是让超人施展拳脚的最佳场所
It's like a superhero's playground!
我在家就不许吃糖球
No Sugar Bombs on my watch.
妈妈在哪
Where's Mom?
她出门上班了
She's up and out.
今天是弹力女超人上班的第一天
She's at her new job doing hero work.
我觉得 现在法律还是规定不许使用超能力吧
But I thought superheroes were still illegal.
没错 是暂时的
They are, for now.
所以妈妈是拿着工资 在做违法的事
So Mom is getting paid to break the law?
她不是做违法的事
She's not breaking...
她在努力工作 努力让超能力合法化
She's an advocate for superheroes.
这是个新工作
It's a new job.
就是说妈妈违反法律使用超能力
So, Mom is going out illegally...
最终的目的是为了超能力的合法化
to explain why she shouldn't be illegal.
你们的校车来了
The bus is here!
快去拿东西 快 快点去
Whoa! Grab your stuff quickly! Go on, get on the...
记得把作业本带上
Put your homework in your pack!
拜拜
Bye-bye!
看来我们两个也能相处的不错
We're gonna get along just fine...
因为你不会问我什么麻烦的问题
'cause you don't ask any hard questions.
准备好了 各部门注意
All right. All locations,
有情况请通知我们
we need to know where you want us.
请待命
Stand by.
这可真奇怪 我居然要在这等着有人犯罪
Seems strange to wait for crime.
放轻松 你现在身处
Relax. You're smack in the middle...
城市里犯罪率最高的地区 非常完美
of the worst crime area in the city. It's perfect.
这里是超人的运动场
It's a superhero's playground.
超人的运动场 好吧
"It's a superhero's playground." Right.
之前我们停止活动的时候
You know, after we went underground...
我老公天天听着警方的通报
my husband used to listen to a police scanner...
等着出点什么乱子
waiting for something to happen.
因为这个我还发火了
And I got mad at him for it.
到头来我跟他一样了
Oh, I'm such a hypocrite.
- 各单位注意 - 有情况了
- All units. - Something's up.
据说有人可能扰乱
We've been picking up some chatter about
悬浮列车的发车仪式
potential disruptions to the hovertrain's opening ceremony.
- 是捣乱还是威胁 - 都有
- Disruption or threat? - Both.
发车仪式在54大街和都金汉路交叉口进行
Station's at Fifty-Fourth and Nottingham.
可能有危险 太棒了
A potential threat! Perfect!
马上去那里 快快快
Fifty-fourth and Nottingham. Go, go, go!
喂 小倩晚上十点半之前必须回家
Hey, Vi! I want you back here by 10:30.
十一点之前
11-ish?
十点之前要不就九点半之前
10-ish, heading for 9:30-ish.
那就十点半之前
10:30-ish it is.
好好看电影吧
Enjoy the movie.
在远方的睡眠国
"In the county of Noddoff...
所有的男孩和女孩
"the Frubbers of Freep...
都要进入甜蜜的梦乡
"are all giving in to the sweet succor of sleep."
我们控制水平线
We will control the horizontal...
我们控制垂直线
we will control the vertical.
那么做和书上的做法不一样吧 爸爸
That's not the way you're supposed to do it, Dad.
他们的标准减法是这样的
They want us to do it this way.
我可不会那样做 难不成数学题还会变么
I don't know that way! Why would they change math?
- 没事 爸爸 - 怎么做不是做
- It's okay, Dad. - Math is math!
我等妈妈回来我在做
I'll just wait for Mom to get back.
什么
What?
这种难题我都不会做 你妈妈也做不了
She won't understand it any better than I do...
外星界限
The Outer Limits.
在远方的睡眠国
"All over Doozle-Dorf,
所有的男孩和女孩都要睡觉
"the Fribbers of Frupp are going to sleep...
因为孩子们的哈欠连天
"'cause they just can't keep up.
在疲倦的睡眠国 大人也要睡觉了
"All over Doozle-Dorf, Doozles are dozing.
他的眼皮渐渐闭上了 头垂下了
"Eyelids so heavy, they're drooping.
最后 重点是
"Closing! The point is:
到了晚上每个人 每个人都躺在床上
"Everyone, everyone's hitting the sack!
大家都睡得特别香
"Everyone's getting the sleep that they lack."
市长们都喜欢吹嘘自己城市
Mayors often brag about their cities...
我也不例外
and I'm no exception.
必须承认
And I'm willing to admit
新城是唯一一座…
that New Urbem is not the only city...
你确定警察不会来找麻烦吗
Are you sure the police are gonna be okay with this?
确定 你这是在帮他们的忙
Sure. You're making life easy for them.
上次我们给警察帮忙
They still haven't forgiven us
到现在他们还记仇呢
for the last time we made life easy for them.
我认识这边的警察局长 不会有问题的
I know the Chief of Police. There won't be a problem.
恕我直言
With all due respect...
要是上次暗中破坏王的事 你自己去搞定
if you alone had handled the Underminer...
结果会不一样的
things would have been different.
我没有别的意思哦
I'm just saying.
而且工程按照预算 提前完工
...on budget and ahead of schedule...
欢迎大家观摩悬浮列车
to launch our magnificent new hovertrain.
乘坐它去往你向往的目的地
It can get you where you need to go
而且速度特别快
at ridiculous speeds.
让列车向着美好的未来前进
The future is open for business!
等等 车停下了
Wait. The train has stopped.
开的方向不对
It's going the wrong direction.
车走的方向不对
It's going the wrong way.
我去追
I'm going after it.
列车的速度是160公里
This thing's really moving.
而且还在加速 现在轨道有多长
100 and climbing. How much track is built?
差不多40公里
About 25 miles.
难道没人能让列车停下来吗
No one can shut this thing down?
试过了 不行
They've tried. No-go.
是弹力女超人吗
Is that Elastigirl?
能远程控制么
Overrides?
他们封锁了系统
They're locked out of the system.
- 能启动保险装置吗 - 时间不够了
- What about a fail-safe? - Not enough time.
有人打电话 我先接一下
Someone's calling! Switching over.
喂 妈妈我找不到运动鞋了
Hey, Mom. I can't find my high-tops
爸爸也找不到
and Dad can't find them either.
但他不愿意打电话问你 所以只能我来问了
But he won't call you and ask, so I am.
别给你妈打电话
Do not call your mother!
小飞 好孩子 我现在不能说话
Dash, honey. Can't talk right now.
找找你床底下 还有多久
Look under your bed, okay. How much time?
不到两分钟
Less than two minutes!
有一条近路 从前面的排气管传过去
There's a shortcut. Cut through the culvert up ahead.
我不知道能不能追上
I don't know if I can stay with it.
那是什么情况
What the heck was that?
大家还好吗 有人受伤吗
Is everybody all right? Is anybody injured?
没事吧
Are you all right?
我看看你在搞什么
Your story better be good.
怎么回事
What happened?
(欢迎回来 弹力女超人 屏霸)
宝贝 你怎么
Honey, why are you...
别问了 什么也别问
Don't say anything.
小倩 你还好吗
It's Dad. Are you okay?
我没事 我只是现在什么话也不想说
I'm fine. I don't wanna talk about it.
托尼没有联系你吗
Tony didn't even call?
我说了我现在不想说话
I don't wanna talk about it.
- 宝贝 你 - 爸
- Oh, honey... - Dad!
你要是真为我好你就让我自己待会行不行
If you want me to feel better, then leave me alone.
我求你了
Please?
我跟你说 警察
See, there's nothing
最讨厌的 就是那种失踪儿童案
a cop hates worse than a missing child.
我弟弟的人儿子 今天是他一周岁生日
My kid brother's son. Today is his first birthday.
如果要说有谁
Oh, but if anybody
能找到那个孩子 就是你了 罗曼
can find that child, it's you, Roman.
因为你是一位出色的警察
Because you're a wonderful policeman.
我们来抢劫了
This is a holdup.
把手举起来 转过身去
All right, get your hands up, turn your back.
把两只手举起来
Put your hands behind
抱着头 不许动
your heads and keep them there!
别动
Don't move!
放下 到那边去
Drop that. All right, now get over there.
看紧大门
Watch the door.
你以为我们开玩笑吗
You think I'm kiddin'?
快点
Now.
我说了 快点
I said now!
我搞定了 我跟你说 快点
I got it! Come on, I tell you, come on!
你想死么
You wanna get killed?
不不
No, no, no!
不
No!
No, no, no.
不
No, no, no!
你也有 超能力
You have powers!
太好了
Yeah, baby,
你身上一点伤都没有
and there's not a scratch on you!
你是不是直接穿过了门
Did you go through the locked door?
拥有穿墙的能力
Are those your powers?
谁这么厉害能变出好多分身
Who can multiply like rabbits
还能任意穿过…
and go right through any solid...
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God!
- 喂 - 嗨亲爱的
- Hello? - Hey, honey.
- 你没给我打电话 - 哦 嘿
- You weren't gonna call me? - Oh, hey!
没打 不是
No. I mean, yes, yeah...
我想打来着
I just didn't wanna wake you.
刚才在院子里发生了很奇特的事
The strangest thing just happened out in the yard.
我是不是把你吵醒了
Sounds like I just woke you up.
没有没有
No, no.
- 只是 小杰他 - 他出事了
- It's just, Jack-Jack... - He had an accident!
我就知道
I knew it!
我现在就回家 我就不该…
I'm coming home right now! I never should have...
小杰没出事 你就安心工作 别担心
No accident. Stay there and finish your mission.
你不应该
You never should...
什么 你觉得我搞不定家务事么
What? You don't think I can do this?
不不 对不起 我说错了
No, no. Sorry. I misspoke.
你需要我回家吗
Do you need me to come back?
不不不 不用 我能搞定 我这很顺利 一切都好
No, no. No, I've got this. Everything's great.
你刚才说小杰怎么了
What happened with Jack-Jack?
没什么 他非常非常健康
Nothing. He's in excellent health.
那就好
Well, that's good.
- 小倩的约会怎么样 - 呃...
- How was Violet's date? - Uh...
约会是在今天晚上 对吧
That was tonight, right?
挺好
Yes. Good.
没有问题 我很好
All fine and good.
小杰有没有闹 乖乖睡着了么
And Jack-Jack went down with no trouble?
对 没错 是的
Fine, yes, no trouble.
小飞的作业 写完了
And Dash got his homework done?
都写完了
All done.
所以 不是我刚一离开家
So, things haven't spiraled out
就乱成一锅粥了
of control the moment I left?
虽然听起来很不可思议
Amazing as it may seem,
今天我和孩子们并没有出任何问题
it has been quite uneventful in fact.
你情况如何
How about you?
我救了一辆列车
I saved a runaway train!
真是太刺激了
It was so great!
市长也在场 参加新列车的剪彩仪式
The mayor was there to cut the ribbon on this new train.
弹力女超人紧随身后
Elastigirl pursued the train
追上列车 并成功救下了…
and was able to successfully activate...
市长说了几句话 剪了彩
Blah, blah, blah. He says a few words, cuts the ribbon...
结果列车一出站
and the train starts pulling
就朝着反方向冲
out of the station backwards...
全新的气垫列车轨道
...track of its brand new hovertrain...
出现故障
...malfunctioned...
多亏了弹力女超人
...thanking Elastigirl...
弹力女超人
Superhero Elastigirl...
Elastigirl...
最后 没人受伤
Boom! No casualties!
驾驶特制的摩托车
...specialized motorbike,
拯救了所有乘客
saving all of the passengers...
一件接着一件
One thing leads to another
然后 我追了上去
and suddenly, I go after it!
我跟你说 真是太险了
I'm telling you, honey, it was a saga!
这真是太棒了 亲爱的
That's fantastic, honey!
你出任务的第一天晚上就这么成功
And on your first night!
我为你感到骄傲
I am so proud of you, really.
我为你也感到骄傲 亲爱的
I'm proud of you, honey.
我知道你也想出来工作 很快就可以了
I know you want to get out there and you will soon.
一定会非常出色的
And you'll be amazing.
我能做到这些
I couldn't have done this
都是因为你把家事都安排好了
if you hadn't taken over so well.
谢谢你为我做了这么多
Thanks for handling everything.
这都没什么
It's nothing.
我爱你 亲爱的 我很快就回去了
I love you, honey. I'll be back soon.
- 做个好梦 - 你也是 亲爱的
- Sweet dreams. - Sweet dreams, honey.
爸爸 没事的
"Hey, Dad, it's okay.
我还是等妈妈回来好了
"I'll just wait for Mom to get home."
说的就像她能…我知道怎么…
As if she could... I know how to...
我能搞定数学题
I can do math.
我的天
Oh, brother...
等妈妈回来
Wait for Mom!
我这算什么 临时父母么
What am I, a substitute parent?
他们改了解法又不是我的错
It's not my fault they changed math.
醒醒 小飞 醒醒
Come on, buddy. Come on.
我好像琢磨出来你的数学作业怎么做了
I think I understand your math assignment.
考试之前还有点时间 我们还来得及复习
We still have some time to finish it before your test.
接着做 把所有的数字
So first, you wanna put all the numbers
都放到等号后面
by themselves on one side.
就要改变正负号
...you change the sign.
也就是说正变成负 负变成正
That means a plus becomes a minus and a minus...
你懂了吗
You got it?
耶 你真棒
Yeah, baby!
你好
Oh. Uh, hello.
我们搬新家了
We're in a new house.
不过我特意在你的柜子门上写了新地址
I did write my address on your locker...
用的还是不褪色的墨水
in permanent ink.
原来这个是你写的
Oh, is that what that is?
你是忘了吗
Did you forget?
忘了 什么
Forget what?
你真逗
That's funny.
给你加一分
Points for funny.
是因为那个奇怪装束的事么
Oh, was it the weird outfit?
这可是有原因的
Because there's a reason.
我们学校有戏曲表演课
I'm in a drama class...
然后 作业是要演莎士比亚的剧
and they just wanna do Shakespeare...
然后就是这种东西让小孩们喜欢看
but they're like, "Try to make it relevant for the kids."
我就说演超人 小孩最喜欢超人
So, like, "Oh, superheroes! Kids love superheroes."
我本来想穿另外一种紧身服的
You wanna wear one kind of tights...
他们说
and then they're like,
不 你得穿别种的
"No, wear these other kind of tights."
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
很多人对于今天的演讲非常关注
Many say your speech today is critical.
两派人都是为人民福祉而努力
Both sides just want the best for their people.
我们马上就能让这地区迎来和平了
We are so close to finally getting peace in the region.
我都好久没上过电视了
I haven't done this in a while.
没关系 救列车就是个好开始
This is good. The train gives us momentum.
你就放心去 展现你平时的魅力
Just go out there and be your charming self...
使其充分发挥作用
and capitalize on it.
弹力女超人 那边已经准备好了
Ms. Elastigirl, they're ready for you.
上台前 伸伸腿
Hey, stretch a leg.
谢谢你 查德 聊得很开心
Thank you, Chad. It was fun.
大使女士 这是你的文件 我们去屋顶乘坐直升机
Ambassador, your documents. We're moving to the rooftop.
大使女士 你好
Oh, Madame Ambassador, hello!
你就是弹力女超人
Oh, you are Elastigirl!
我一定得跟你握握手
This is why now I'm shaking your hand.
之前你被迫隐姓埋名 我很难过
It was so sad when you went underground.
看到你现在身着华丽的超能装 重现于世 我真高兴
I am glad to see you back in your shiny outfit.
您跟我说这些我深受鼓舞
That means so much coming from you.
祝您演讲顺利
Good luck with your speech.
走这边 大使女士
This way, Ambassador.
要让和平永存
Bring lasting peace!
我会的 你也要继续打击犯罪
I will, when you defeat evil.
好的
Okay.
三…二…
Three, two...
过去十五年里
For over 15 years,
超人们一直隐姓埋名
superheroes have been in hiding.
生活在一个
Forced into it by a society
不愿意帮助 支持他们的社会
no longer willing to support them.
现在不一样了
That may soon be changing...
因为社会上出现了支持超人回归的运动
due to a growing movement to bring the Supers back.
今天我们请来了
Here, fresh on the heels of her own
列车失控事件中力挽狂澜
heroic save of a runaway train...
以闪亮形象出现在世人面前的 弹力女超人
and sporting a new look, is the superhero, Elastigirl.
- 欢迎你 - 你好 查德
- Welcome! - Hello, Chad.
现在看来你的支持率很高啊
All the polls are going in your direction.
的确是 这是好事
That's true. Things are good...
你好
Hello.
嘿
Uh, hello?
你注意到我了么
Do I have your attention?
是的 查德
Yes, Chad.
当然你注意到我了
Of course I do.
我出现在你的屏幕上
I'm appearing on your screen.
读着另一个屏幕上别人让我说的话
Reading the words I'm saying off of another screen.
屏幕无处不在
Screens are everywhere.
屏幕能控制我们的生活
We are controlled by screens.
而掌控者 就是我
And screens are controlled by me...
屏霸
Screenslaver.
我控制者这次采访
I control this broadcast...
也控制着坐在你面前的这个愚蠢的主持人
and this idiotic anchorman you see before you.
他是怎么了
What's wrong with him?
信号遭到劫持 我去检查
The signal's been hijacked. I'll check it out.
记住 千万不要看屏幕
Don't look at any monitors.
我们可以在空中
I could hijack the ambassador's aerocade...
直接劫持大使乘坐的直升机
while it's still airborne.
对吧 弹力女超人
Right, Elastigirl?
最近的窗户 最近的窗户在哪
Nearest window! Where's the nearest window?
- 怎么回事 - 弹力女超人去哪了
- Oh, what's going on? - Where's Elastigirl?
是哪个呢
Which one?
弹力女超人 你在这干什么
Elastigirl! What are you doing here?
大使现在有危险了 她乘坐的是哪架直升机…
The ambassador is in danger. Which chopper is she...
小心
Look out!
跟上去 尽量接近点
Follow them and get me close!
赶紧找个地方安全降落
Get out of the sky, and touch down safely!
退后 弹力女超人
Stand down! It's Elastigirl.
回到座位上 大使
Stay in your seat, ma'am!
我们遭到了袭击
We're under attack!
快点去 快去保护大使
Quick, go! Protect the ambassador!
把舱门打开
Open the door!
快照她说的做
Do as she says!
你们都会游泳吗
Can you all swim?
- 会的 - 不会
- Yeah. - No!
我们马上就要弹射了 都别动
We're gonna have to slingshot! Hang on!
你没事吧 大使
Are you all right, ma'am?
我 我没事
I'm perfectly fine...
男生们都是混蛋 超能力最没用了
Boys are jerks and superheroes suck.
早上好
Good morning!
他就看了一眼我穿超能装的样子
He takes one look at me in that suit...
第二天见到我的时候他就假装不认识我
and decides to pretend he doesn't even know me.
他也是在保护自己
He's protecting himself.
要是他真的看到了你 还是忘掉比较好
If he really did see you, it's best that he forget.
对你也有好处
It's better for you, too.
我都记不清这些年
I can't tell you how many memories
迪瑞克消除了多少记忆
Dicker's had to erase over the years...
就是有人发现了
when someone figured out
我和你妈妈超人身份的时候
your mother's or my identity.
是迪瑞克搞的鬼
It was Dicker!
- 你和他说了托尼的事 - 小倩
- You told him about Tony! - Honey...
都是因为叫迪瑞克抹除了托尼的记忆 所以他才会忘了我
You had me erased from Tony's mind!
我恨死超能力了
I hate superheroes!
我再也不要做超人了
And I renounce them!
我不要做超人啦
I renounce them!
姐这是青春期叛逆吗
Is she having adolescence?
最新的报告表明
A new report out today shows that,
关于决策问题
when it comes to decision-making...
人们觉得 通过让猴子扔飞镖的方式做决定
people have more trust in a monkey
比让国会议员们决定更靠谱
throwing darts than Congress.
怎么了托尼 有抗议吗
What's going on, Tommy? A protest?
这些人是来声援的
They're here in support.
声援？ 声援什么
Support? Support of what?
他们是来声援你的
Well, in support of you.
谢谢你们能来
Thanks for coming out. Hi.
嗨 哦天呢 真是太谢谢了
Oh, my goodness. Thanks so much.
你好
Oh, hello.
你拿的什么牌子啊
What does your sign say?
(屏霸仍然逍遥法外)
超人应该合法化
Supers should be legal now!
我跟你说 你才知道啊
Talk to ya. Oh, what do ya know!
艾伦伍德
Ellenwood.
你现在想起回我电话
Oh, now you wanna return my calls
聊超人的事了
about superheroes, huh?
过会我再联系你
Oh. I'll have to call you back.
真是太好了
Oh, that felt good.
菲利西亚 让那边别挂电话
Felicia, hold my calls, please.
起作用啦
Hey! It's working!
大使今天刚刚发表了
Hey, the ambassador made a big speech
关于超能力的重要演讲
about superheroes today.
看来救人
Turns out saving someone's life
还是能给他们留下好印象的 想不到吧
makes a good impression on them. Who knew, huh?
我接到了来自世界各地的电话
I'm getting calls from all over the world.
媒体曝光率提高了72%
Media awareness is up 72%.
超能力合法化已经成为
The push for superhero legalization
世界名列前茅的潮流
is becoming a worldwide movement!
下一阶段我还有个大计划
I have big plans for our next move.
我们要在还是举办一次海上峰会
We're gonna have a summit at sea.
就用我们的船
We'll use our ship...
把世界各地的超人和领导人
we'll gather leaders and Supers...
- 都请到船上去 - 太棒了
- from all over the world. - That's great.
我很高兴
I'm happy.
我很高兴支持率上升
I'm happy the numbers are up.
很高兴大使也支持合法化
I'm happy the ambassador is pro-superhero...
看到你高兴 我也很欣喜
and I'm happy you're happy.
你嘴上出很高兴 可是 我怎么感觉不到呢
I'm hearing that you're happy, but why am I not feeling it?
因为我还没有抓住他
Because I didn't get him!
屏霸还在外面害人
Screenslaver is still out there.
我按照他的游戏规则走 赢了这一轮
All I did was play his game and win this round.
他一定不会善罢甘休
He's gonna want more
等他出手的时候 我们肯定输
and as long as he gets to play, he wins.
我做生意其中一条心得就是
One thing I've learned in business?
好好的享受当下
Smell the flowers.
鲜花难得开一次
They don't bloom that often.
不然将来你的墓碑上会写着
What do you want on your tombstone?
她操心到老
"She worried a lot"?
别再说了
All right, stop talking.
带她去看看
Show her.
这真是太令人兴奋了
This is just so exciting, isn't it? Huh?
哇
Oh, wow. Uh...
弹力女超人 你来啦
Wow! Elastigirl, there you are.
- 你好 - 我没想到
- Hello. - I didn't...
凯伦 你快振作一点
Come on, get yourself together, Karen.
嗨 我是穿越侠
Hi, my superhero name is Voyd.
我就是 很想感激你 那个 敢于站出来
I just wanna thank you, for, like, for being you!
好了 让我来展示一下我的超能力
Okay, what I can do, um, is this.
好了
Yeah.
非常精彩 有多维度的
That is impressive. Very interdimensional.
我之前觉得自己被社会摈弃了
I felt like an outcast before.
我现在 自从你勇敢现身之后我就觉得
But now, with you being you, I feel like...
我 做回自己了
Yay, me.
我用飞机把他们从世界各地接过来
I flew them in from all over.
之前他们都不现身的
They've all been in hiding.
他们有各种各样的超能力 身份长期保密
They have powers, secret identities...
还给自己起了名号
and names they've given themselves.
我是人鹰侠 很高兴见到你
I'm Screech. It's a pleasure.
我一直认为超人最好的榜样
I've always considered you
就应该是你这样的
the gold standard for superheroes.
谢谢您 您太客气了
Well, thanks. You're too nice.
我的名字叫 飞砖侠
I am called Brick.
很高兴见到你 你从哪里来
Nice to meet you, Brick. Uh, where are you from?
威斯康辛州
Wisconsin.
哦 弹力女超人 他想你的能力是
Oh. Elastigirl. I assume your powers are...
用电流进行打击
You know, zapping things electrically...
充电啊 发出闪电啊之类的
charging things, bolts of lightning, that kind of stuff.
我叫反胃侠
Name's Reflux.
你可能觉得这其实是胃病 或是超能力
Medical condition or superpower, you decide.
我就是讲个笑话
That's a little line
让大家轻松一下
I say just to put people at ease.
你不介意吧
Hope I don't offend.
不不不 你说的很好
Oh, no, no, no. Reflux. Love it.
我很期待能跟你共事
Well, I do look forward to working with you.
这能力太棒了 保持住
Yes, that is impressive. Keep practicing.
我很高兴 今天很成功 祝贺你们
Well, I'm beat. Congratulations. Big day.
晚安 女士们 我们明天早上再见
Good night, ladies. I will see you tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
感觉不错
Must be nice for you,
隔了这么久再一次成为焦点
being out front after all this time.
成为焦点
Out front?
是啊 毕竟上次当超人已经是很久之前的事了
Well, it's been a while since your superhero days...
那时候 感觉你只是
and even then, you were kind of
活在超能先生的阴影里
in Mr. Incredible's shadow.
对此我可不敢苟同
Nah, I beg to differ.
我可没说你不够耀眼 你很耀眼
I'm not... I'm not saying you weren't big.
今天你可算的上是超级巨星了
No, you were, and are, a superstar...
可是 现在的舞台是完全属于你一人
but you have the stage to yourself now.
人们的注意力想不集中在你身上都难
And people have to pay attention.
所以你准备扯"这是个男人的世界"这套说辞咯
Oh, you mean, "It's a man's world" and all that?
那你觉得现在的世界是怎么样的
Well, what world do you live in?
你哥哥是公司的总裁
Your brother runs DEVTECH.
我才不想做他的工作 我搞发明 他负责推销
I don't want his job. I invent, he sells.
我现在问你 我们两个谁的影响力更大
I ask you, which of us has the greater influence?
我这人有两面
Which side of me are you asking?
理想家 还是批评家 你想问哪一种
The believer or the cynic?
批评家吧
The cynic...
那我觉得 推销的工作更重要
Would say selling is more important
因为推销员越厉害 吸引的顾客越多
because the best sellers have the most buyers.
甚至卖什么都不重要
Doesn't matter what you're selling.
最重要的是如何吸引人们来买
It only matters what people buy.
你说的很对
This is true.
如果有一天我能揭示宇宙起源的真相
If I discovered the origin of the universe...
我哥哥也能想办法
my brother would find a way
把它包装成一种 足部按摩疗法
to market it as a, uh, foot massager.
那么 理想家会如何看待这个问题
So, what would the believer say?
理想家认为 你要活出自己的风格
The believer would tell you to make your mark.
不用看别人的眼色表达自己 坚持自己的主张
Don't wait for permission, assert yourself
用自己的意志改变现状
and impose your will on the status quo.
- 你说话很像我哥哥 - 什么
- Sounds like my brother. - What?
你说话很像我哥哥
You sound like my brother.
那他做的没错啊
Well, he's not wrong.
要想得到他人的回应 这可算得上一门技术活了
There is an art to getting a reaction...
我知道怎么抓到他了
Oh! I know how to get him.
- 抓我哥哥么 - 不 我是说屏霸
- My brother? - No. Screenslaver!
你可是技术专家 我需要锁定某个信号
You're tech-savvy. I need to lock onto a signal...
追踪它的来源
and trace its origin.
你最快要花多久能把所需的设备弄好
How fast can you slap something together
然后跟我在机场会面
and meet me at the airport?
去机场
Airport?
我需要立马出城一趟
Need to go out of town, pronto.
我明早五点就能准备好设备
I can get your contraption together by 5:00 a.m.
我们得上电视 联系查德
I need to get on TV. Chad!
今晚就让我哥哥安排查德
I'll get my brother to set up an exclusive with him
在新闻节目里对你进行专访
tonight on the newscast.
直接用电话连线
Finish our interview by phone!
提高知名度
Promote the hell out of it.
脱离屏霸的控制
Independence from Screenslavery!
- 查德新闻频道 - 一举成功
- Chad tonight. - Boom!
- 我是迪瑞克 - 嘿 迪瑞克
- Dicker. - Yeah, hey, Rick.
你还记得我跟你提过的
You remember that kid I mentioned to you?
那个叫托尼·莱丁格的孩子吗
Tony Rydinger.
那个消除记忆的小男孩吧 记得那孩子看起来不错的
Mind wipe? Yeah, nice kid.
你还消除了
Well, you also wiped out
他周五晚上要和我女儿巴小倩约会的记忆
the Friday night date my daughter had with him.
严格说来他把小倩彻底忘了
In fact, you wiped out my daughter.
抱歉 这项技术还不成熟 鲍勃
Oops. Not an exact science, Bob.
瑞克 你一定得帮帮我
Rick, you gotta help me here.
小倩快恨死我了 还有你 恨超能力
Violet hates me, and you, and superheroes.
我得想办法补救一下 托尼的资料你手上有多少
I gotta fix this. What do you know about Tony?
没有多少
Not much.
看起来是个挺守规矩的孩子
Seems like a good kid.
受欢迎 喜欢运动 音乐
Popular, plays sports, music.
父母开了家餐馆 叫"快乐拼盘" 他有时候也会在餐馆帮忙
Parents own The Happy Platter, kid works there part time.
"快乐拼盘"
Happy Platter?
我们干嘛要开车跑这么远
Why did we drive all the way across town
来这个"快乐拼盘"餐馆
for The Happy Platter?
我们要那边的四人座 靠着树林的那个桌子
We'd like a booth over there, near the philodendron.
是不是很不错 坐在树林附近
Good, right? Near the philodendron.
这个快乐餐馆 我看一点都不快乐
This platter doesn't look all that happy to me.
看起来挺无聊的
It looks bored.
那就成了无聊大拼盘
Ha-ha! The Bored Platter!
我觉得小倩肯定吃腻了路边的快餐
I thought Vi would want a change of pace
要换换口味
from drive-in food.
我喜欢吃路边的快餐
I like drive-in food.
换换口味该不是只吃蔬菜吧
Does this mean vegetables?
营养要平衡就得吃蔬菜 孩子们
A balanced diet means vegetables, kiddo.
要习惯多吃蔬菜
Get used to it.
各位晚上好
Good evening, everyone.
啊 我的天
Oh, no!
- 她没事吧 - 小倩 你没事吧
- Is she all right? - Violet, are you okay?
没什么好看的
Nothing to see here.
可能你需要更多餐巾纸
Yeah, more napkins would be good.
- 我没事 我没事 - 这种情况总是会出现的
- I'm fine, I'm fine. - It happens all the time here.
马上就擦干
Mops it right up.
她平时喝东西的时候 可没有这么激动
Normally, she doesn't ever drip like this.
- 你们还要水吗 先生 - 要的
- Would you like water, sir? - Yes.
来些水吧 这是我女儿
Yes, I would. This is my daughter...
- 你一定认识的 对吧 - 我的天 别说了
- who you must know, right? - God. Stop.
- 你好 - 她叫小倩
- Hello. - Violet.
你好 小倩
Hello, Violet.
嘿 小倩 打个招呼
Hey, Vi, say hi to...
别逼我 爸爸
Don't push it, Dad.
我叫巴小飞 是她弟弟
I'm Dash, her little brother.
你好
Hello.
这水的味道真是不错
Mmm. This is really good water.
很是清新
It's very refreshing.
山泉水 对吧
Spring water, is it?
我不知道 先生 应该就是自来水吧
I don't know, sir. I think it's tap.
不过非常好
Well, it is very good.
非常棒的自来水
Excellent tap.
抱歉
Excuse me.
很高兴认识你们
Well, nice to meet you.
- 她干嘛去了 - 嗯
- Where'd she go? - Mmm.
找地方发火去了
To find a good place to be angry?
今晚我们要连线采访一位特别嘉宾
Tonight, we go now to a special remote interview...
弹力女超人
with Elastigirl.
你怎么样 查德
How you feeling, Chad?
最近还好吗
You doing all right?
我很好 医生给我做了检查
I'm fine. The doctors checked me out.
我根本不记得当时的事了
I have no memory of the event.
实话跟你说 看到录像里
I gotta tell you, it's pretty strange
前几天的我
to see a recording...
自己却一点印象都没有 感觉真的很奇怪
of yourself the night before and have no recollection.
大家不用担心
I don't think anyone needs to worry.
今天晚上我们的安全措施非常的严密
We've taken many precautions tonight though.
你现在在哪
Where are you right now?
我在调查一个案子 在一个视野开阔 安全的地方
On a case, in a secure undisclosed location.
我想先聊聊你
I wanna talk about you...
先从最近救下失控列车的事迹开始吧
starting with your save of a runaway train.
这里有一段独家的未经过编辑的录像
Here's an exclusive unedited clip
是装在你身上的摄像头记录下来的
from your own suit cam.
请播放录像吧
Roll the clip.
列车动起来了
This thing's really moving.
列车的速度是160公里每小时 而且还在加速 已经建好的轨道有多长
100 and climbing. How much track is built?
差不多四十公里吧
About 25 miles.
屏霸中止了这个节目
The Screenslaver interrupts this program...
有重要的事情要宣布
for an important announcement.
丫的 她猜中了
I'll be damned. She knew.
接下来就看你的设备管不管用了
Let's see if your gadget works.
剩下的录像就不用看了
Don't bother watching the rest.
抓到你了
Gotcha!
弹力女超人无法拯救城市
Elastigirl doesn't save the day.
只是推迟了自己失败之日的到来而已
She only postpones her defeat.
可她至少还在努力
And while she postpones her defeat...
而你们只会吃着薯片 看着她解决
you eat chips and watch her confront problems...
那些你们自己懒得解决的问题
that you are too lazy to deal with.
超人们满足了你们愚蠢的愿望
Superheroes are part of your brainless desire...
用虚拟代替真实生活的愿望
to replace true experience with simulation.
你们不会说话 只会看脱口秀
You don't talk, you watch talk shows.
天天就看那些有奖竞赛节目
You don't play games, you watch game shows.
旅行 恋爱 冒险
Travel, relationships, risk...
所有的这些有意义的人生经历
every meaningful experience must be packaged...
都包装在电视节目里 供你们远远的观赏
and delivered to you to watch at a distance.
所以你们就能一直躲在家里
So that you can remain ever sheltered...
被动接受这些
ever passive...
变成了贪婪的消费者
ever ravenous consumers...
一直躺在沙发上面
who can't bring themselves to rise from their couches...
不努力 这都不是真正的生活
break a sweat and participate in life.
你们想受到超人们的保护
You want superheroes to protect you...
而你们也因为有人保护你们 变得越发软弱
and make yourselves ever more powerless in the process.
你们自认为 会有人照顾你们的
While you tell yourselves you're being looked after.
会有人给你们开创美好未来
That your interests are being served.
会有人维护你们的权利
And your rights are being upheld.
长此以往 现有的体制一面榨干你们的血
So that the system can keep stealing from you...
另一面还对你们报以微笑
smiling at you all the while.
来呀 叫你们的超人走狗们来阻止我啊
Go ahead, send your Supers to stop me.
你们就吃着零食 看看电视
Grab your snacks, watch your screens,
走着瞧吧
and see what happens.
你们已不再是局面的掌控者
You are no longer in control.
我才是
I am.
找到了什么吗
Find anything?
抱歉
Sorry!
什么情况
What happened?
你还问什么情况 你把那些证据都给毁了
What happened is you destroyed my evidence.
这是怎么回事 我犯什么法了
What's going on? What did I do?
你们这些家伙要干什么
What did you guys do to me?
厉害啊 你个小混混 还怪体制不行啊
That's right, punk. Blame the system.
你的追踪器太好用了 伊芙琳
Your tracker worked like a charm, Evelyn.
你真是个天才
You're a genius.
得了吧
Aw, shucks!
我只是你这个天才背后的天才
I'm just the genius behind the genius.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
我们今天又开始学分数 小数和 百分数了
We're doing fractions and denismals and percentages
我题目做不来
and I don't get 'em.
你不是
Aren't you...
上次不是学会了吗
Didn't we get all caught up?
对 我上次是学会了
Yeah, we were caught up...
我们现在学的是分数 百分数和小"书"
and now we're doing fractions and percentages and demicels.
小数不是小"书"
Decimals.
关于超能跑车的最新情况
...the addition of the Incredibile,
它之前的主人
the super car...
是那位著名的超人 超能先生
once driven by superhero, Mr. Incredible.
这玩意 只有等你富可敌国的时候才买得起
It's the kind of thing you buy when you have everything else.
他们说车子已经修不好了
They said it was beyond repair.
你看 车的状态非常好
Hey, it was in perfect condition.
这是你原来的车
You used to drive that?
他们还说车子彻底毁了
They said it was destroyed.
之前人们以为这辆车已经被毁或者不翼而飞
Long thought lost or destroyed,
但这辆车还是出现在私人拍卖会上
the famous car turned up at private auction.
他们说 车已经
They said it was...
那是我的车
That's my car!
这愚蠢的瀑布
Stupid water feature!
这辆车装有一些非常棒的配件
This car is just loaded with amazing gadgets.
愿意介绍一下么
Care to demonstrate?
我也希望介绍给大家 但我们现在还没搞清楚
I'd love to, but we haven't figured out
如何启动这些装备
how to make them work yet.
哇 是你在操控么
Wow! It works?
你在干什么 小飞 这可不是你的玩具
What are you doing? This is not a toy!
你启动了火箭炮
That's a rocket launcher!
太棒了 按哪个键能发射火箭
Sweet! Which one launches the rocket?
这又不是你的车
Hey! This is not your car!
那也不是你的车
It's not your car, either!
是我的车 这是超能跑车
It is so! It's the Incredibile.
- 那车怎么在那个人手上 - 车不应该在他手上
- Why's that guy have it? - He shouldn't!
发射火箭 火箭
Launch the rockets! Launch the rockets!
火箭 发射
Launch the rockets!
- 我们不会乱发射火箭的 - 我要炸炸炸
- I'm not launching anything! - I wanna blow it up!
你以为我会让那个有钱的家伙
Do you think I want an angry rich guy...
来找我麻烦吗
coming after me right now...
- 我都尽量不去 - 我都不知道
- when I'm trying not to... - I'm not sure
- 这里是什么情况 马克 - 让你妈妈为我们分心
- what's happened here, Mark. - Distract your mother.
这里的人们都散开了
But everyone here has scattered
我觉得我们应该马上撤离
and I'm afraid I'll need to move at any minute.
我的车在这有钱人手上
Rich guy got my car.
老爸 你不去把跑车
So, you're not gonna steal your car
从那个有钱人那里偷回来吗
back from the rich guy?
那是什么玩意
What the heck is that?
小杰居然有超能力
Jack-Jack has powers?
对呀 但是
Well, yeah, but...
- 你早就知道了 - 是的
- You knew about this? - Yeah.
- 为什么你不告诉我们 - 我说不好
- Why didn't you tell us? - I don't know.
我们可是你的孩子 我们有权知道这些事
We're your kids. We need to know these things.
- 告诉妈妈了吗 - 没有
- Did you tell Mom? - No.
- 为什么不说 - 你妈妈
- Why not? - Your mother is not...
你肯定是不想让我们不知道吧
You'd want us to tell you, wouldn't you?
- 你为什么不告诉妈妈 - 因为我不想让她
- Why would you not tell Mom? - Because I didn't wanna...
什么
What?
- 别这样 爸爸 - 我现在还不是时候
- Come on, man. - Because it's not the time.
- 你怎么能这样 - 为什么
- Why? - Because...
这样真不好
So uncool!
因为我还没想好怎么说 行了吧
Because I'm formulating, okay?
我也刚知道这个事 我需要消化
I'm taking in information, I'm processing!
我要学做数学题 还要补救男朋友的事
I'm doing the math, I'm fixing the boyfriend...
还要哄好小杰
and keeping the baby
免得他变成喷火的怪物
from turning into a flaming monster!
我要怎么同时做好这么多事
How do I do it?
我是在努力适应环境 孩子们
By rolling with the punches, baby!
我不能胡乱做一通就完事了
I eat thunder and crap lightning, okay?
因为我是著名的超能先生
'Cause I'm Mr. Incredible!
不是能力不足先生 也不是一般般先生
Not Mr. So-So or Mr. Mediocre-Guy.
我是超能先生
Mr. Incredible!
应该找鲁修斯叔叔帮忙
We should call Lucius.
不 我自己能处理
No. I can handle it.
我绝对不会去求…
There's no way I'm gonna...
爸爸
Dada.
我去给鲁修斯叔叔打电话
I'm calling Lucius.
我看挺正常的 是什么时候开始的
Looks normal to me. When did this start happening?
从何莉开始工作的时候开始的
Since Helen got the job.
- 那她应该知道这事吧 - 你开玩笑吧
- I assume she knows? - Are you kidding?
我肯定不能跟她说这事
I can't tell her about this,
她可在外面忙那些超人的工作呢
not while she's doing hero work!
妈妈
Mama!
女士们 加把劲
Girls, come on.
怎么能光让男人们做拯救世界的工作
Leave the saving the world to the men?
- 我觉得这样不行 - 妈妈
- I don't think so. - Mama!
我一定要成功的照顾好孩子们
I've got to succeed!
这样的话 她在外面才能成功
So she can succeed.
- 所以 咱们一家都能成功 - 我明白你的意思 鲍勃
- So we can succeed! - I get it, Bob!
你有多久没睡觉了
I get it. When was the last time you slept?
谁还记得睡觉的事啊
Who keeps track of that?
毕竟他还只是婴儿而已嘛
Besides, he's a baby.
我能搞定的 我自己就能搞定
I can handle it, I got this handled.
这么说 你能搞定 是吧
So, you good then?
一切都尽在你掌握之中 对吧
You got everything under control? Right?
怎么回事
What the...?
小杰宝宝 想吃饼干吗
Cookie! Cha Cha want a cookie?
好吃的饼干 小杰宝宝
Num-num cookie? Cha Cha wanna num-num?
好吃的饼干
Num-num cookie! Cookie!
- 你没… - 饼干
- You're not... - Cookie!
- 好吃的饼干 - 我的天
- Oh, my God! - Cookie!
- 爸爸 爸爸 - 哇
- Dada! Dada. Dada. - Whoa.
也就是说他还能听见你 哪怕是在…
So, he can still hear you from the...
在四维空间也能听见 对
From the other dimension, yeah.
这个很怪 感觉不太妙
That is freaky. I mean, that's not like...
不像我的那两个孩子 对 他就是不像
Not like our other kids. No, it is not.
充满能量 随时随地都可能发动
Full powers, totally random.
那现在他算是 在那吧
So now, he's what? Is he good?
对呀 他看起来很好 对吧
Yeah, you'd think so, right?
可是我总不能一直给他吃饼干吧
Obviously, I can't keep giving him cookies!
- 呃呃 - 要是我不给他
- Uh-uh? - But if I stop...
他又在胡闹了 又在闹了
Ahhh! He is freaking! Again, he is freaking!
不 不准咬你爸爸
No biting the daddy!
- 这是什么... - 不准乱咬
- What the...? - No biting!
好吧
Okay.
我应该只是需要一点时间做自己的事
I think I just need a little bit of me time.
然后我就能好起来了
Then I'll be good to go.
这可不是一点点时间的问题 鲍勃
Oh, you need more than me time, Bob.
你需要在许多方面
You need major life realignment
调整自己的生活方式
on a number of levels.
首先就要想办法搞定这个小怪物
Starting with baby superfreak here!
你需要的是新想法 而不是这些老套路
You need some solid outside-the-box thinking.
戈尔巴基
Galbaki?
弹力女超人的超能装居然是找戈尔巴基做的
Elastigirl's supersuit is by Galbaki?
你给我好好解释一下
Explain yourself!
我的天 你怎么憔悴成这个样子
Oh, my God. You're worse than I thought.
我来找你是因为小杰的事 我把他带过来了
It's the baby. I brought the baby.
这倒是很少见
Oh, highly unusual.
你脸色太差了 鲍勃
You look ghastly, Robert.
我都没怎么睡觉
I haven't been sleeping.
我伤了女儿的心 也不会做新数学题
I broke my daughter, they keep changing math...
学校要带五号电池 可我买成了二号电池
we needed double-A batteries, but I got triple-A's...
现在还是没有五号电池
and now we still need double-A batteries.
我把红衣服和白衣服放在一起洗
I put one red thing in a load of whites
结果都洗成了粉色的
and now everything's pink.
我们家鸡蛋也快没了
And I think we need eggs.
只要能把孩子养好 也是非常伟大的
Done properly, parenting is a heroic act.
前提是养得好
Done properly.
幸运的是 这个问题从来都没有困扰过我
I am fortunate that it has never afflicted me.
你来我这 不是为了
But you do not come to me
要鸡蛋和电池的吧 鲍勃
for eggs and batteries, Robert.
我是设计超能装的
I design herowear
弹力女超人必须换一件新超能服
and Elastigirl must have a new suit.
我来这是为了小杰
Actually, it's Jack-Jack.
你想给小婴儿也做一件超能装么
You also wish a new suit for the baby?
现在他还小 应该没那么急着穿超能服
I would hardly classify this as an emergency.
他这个是特殊情况 很值得研究
Well, he's a special case. Worth studying.
我能不能把他放在你这一阵子
If I could just leave him with you for a while...
你说把他放在这
Leave him? Here?
我这人可不喜欢带孩子 鲍勃
I am not a baby person, Robert.
我这也没有孩子用的东西 我是个艺术家
I have no baby facilities. I am an artist.
我绝对不会做这种琐碎又平庸的
I do not involve myself in the prosaic day-to-day to...
事情
day.
真厉害
Fascinating!
你看到了吗 鲍勃
Are you seeing this, Robert?
爸爸
Dada.
我的天呢
Oh, my God.
厉害
Yes!
你当然可以把小杰留在我这
Of course you can leave the baby overnight.
何莉不在家 你做家务
I'm sure filling in for Helen is challenging,
也一定也很累
and you are very tired...
那两个孩子也需要你照顾
and the other children need you
他们想你了 赶紧回家去吧
and miss you, and you must go to them.
莫衣娜阿姨会照顾好小杰的
Auntie Edna will take care of everything...
好好开车注意安全 再见 感谢你的到访
so, drive safely and goodbye. I enjoy our visits.
莫衣娜 阿姨
"Auntie Edna"?
请注意 请注意
Attention. Attention.
我想感谢今晚到场的所有人
I wanna thank everyone that came out tonight...
你们支持超人事业
in support of superheroes...
让他们得以重见天日
and bringing them back into society!
是你们推动了进步
You all made it happen.
我们的社会对超人的需要之迫切
The need for this has been made
最近尤为突出
crystal clear in recent days...
有些跳梁小丑 比如那个自称屏霸的家伙
with bad actors like the self-proclaimed
威胁着社会稳定
Screenslaver threatening our peace.
可他没闹腾多久就完蛋了
His reign was short, huh?
我觉得这一切要感谢这位女士
And thanks to this woman...
伟大的超人 你们都爱她 也都想见她
a great super. You love her. You missed her.
欢迎回来 弹力女超人
Welcome back, Elastigirl.
快上来 别害羞了
Come on up here. Don't be bashful.
来吧 到台上来
Come on. Get up here.
我想把这个送给你
I want you to have this.
做个纪念
A memento.
谢谢温斯顿 伊芙琳 还有迪沃科技的全体员工
Thanks, Winston, Evelyn, and everyone at DEVTECH.
我永远感谢你们
I am forever in your debt.
也感谢到场的各位
And thanks to all of you,
是你们的支持改变了大家对超人的看法
your pressure changed all the right minds.
我们在很短时间内取得了非常大的进展
We've made amazing headway in a very short time...
所以我现在要宣布一个重要消息
which leads me to an important announcement.
就在刚才的一场世界级的峰会上
Just now, at a worldwide summit...
超过一百个国家的领导人
leaders from more than a hundred
已经达成了共识
of the world's top countries...
致力于推动超能力的合法化
have agreed to make superheroes legal again!
我们会邀请
We'll gather superheroes and leaders
世界各地的领导人和超人
from all over the planet...
来到我们的正义号轮船上
on our boat, the Everjust...
参加国际协定的签署仪式 全程通过直播
for a televised signing ceremony at sea.
现在各位别耽搁了 大家赶快上船
Now if you'll excuse us, we got a ship to catch!
很高兴见到你 谢谢你能来
So good to see you. Thanks for coming out.
你好 我又来了
Hey. Hi, it's me, again.
那个 我一直想问你个问题
Um, there's, uh, something I've always wanted to ask you.
你是怎么平衡超人工作
Yeah, how do you balance the superhero stuff
和日常生活的
with the life stuff?
我能处理好超人的任务
I know I can handle the superhero stuff.
抱歉 我有事要稍微离开一下
Would you please excuse me a moment?
好的 那一会再聊 谢谢
Oh. Yeah, okay, see you later! Good talk!
- 嗨 小倩 - 嗨
- Hey, Vi. - Hey.
小杰怎么没回来
Where's Jack-Jack?
莫衣娜夫人会照顾他
E's taking him for a little bit.
- 莫衣娜会看孩子么 - 是啊
- Edna is babysitting? - Yeah.
所以你就把小杰留给他了
And you're okay with this?
对 我也不知道为什么但我就这么做了
Yeah. I don't know why, but yeah.
我有些话想跟你说
I wanted to say something to you.
托尼的事 我很抱歉
Sorry about Tony.
我没想到迪瑞克会抹掉托尼的记忆
I didn't think about Dicker erasing his memory...
也没想到 你要为你自己从没做过的选择
or about you having to pay the price for a choice...
付出代价 这不公平 我知道
you never made. It's not fair, I know.
后来在餐馆里 我又雪上加霜
And then, I made it worse at the restaurant
让你去
by trying to...
反正 不管怎么说
Anyway. Anyway...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
过去我一直很确定
I'm used to knowing
自己做的事情是对的
what the right thing to do is...
可现在我说不好了
but now, I'm not sure anymore.
我只想当一个
I just wanna be...
好爸爸
a good dad.
你不是一般的好爸爸
You're not good.
是超级好
You're super.
超人在工作的时候允许喝一点酒吗
Are superheroes allowed to drink on duty?
我现在绝对不是在工作 虽然穿着制服
I'm definitely not on duty. Ignore the costume.
我知道我应该上去
I know I should be up there...
不过总和人微笑握手我有些累了 我想清静一会
but I had to step away from the grip and grins, you know?
一个人才能平静下来 我也是这样
Gotta get away to keep it pure. I know I do.
你在躲着什么人吗
What are you getting away from?
就是公司那些人 主要是我哥哥
Eh, you know, company stuff. My brother, mostly.
你很爱他呀 你们俩就是公司的
But you love him, you two are this company.
阴阳两面
Yin and yang.
是啊 我做发明 他和人打交道
Yeah, I invent the stuff, he's good at people.
让他们高兴 搞清楚他们想要什么
Pleasing them, engaging them, figuring out what they want.
我从来不懂人们想要什么
I never know what people want.
你觉得他们要什么
What do you think they want?
方便
Ease.
人们每次都会放弃质量 选择轻松的东西
People will trade quality for ease every time.
这东西很差 不过你看它们方便
It may be crap, but hey, it's convenient.
这次的案子也有这种感觉
Yeah. Kind of like this case.
你说什么 屏霸的这个案子么
What? The Screenslaver?
对 有些事情不太对劲
Yeah, something's not sitting right.
这也太简单了
It was too easy.
抓住屏霸简单 哇哦
That was too easy? Wow.
- 有意思 - 什么
- Funny. - What?
看看这里
Look at that.
屏霸藏身的地方有一块屏幕 连通了我身上的摄像头
One of Screenslaver's monitors is tuned into my suit cam.
是嘛
What?
这个摄像头不是闭路连接的吗
Isn't the suit cam closed circuit?
是的
It is.
那为什么在屏霸那会有图像
Then how come Screenslaver has it?
也许他黑进了系统
Maybe he hacked it?
这么说他有能力黑进闭路系统
So, he's sophisticated enough to do that...
藏身处却只挂了一把锁
but he has simple locks on his doors?
也许他是有意让你找到的
Maybe he wanted you to find him.
他是想让自己被抓吗
He wanted to get caught?
他是想让你赢
He wanted you to win.
可是这不合逻辑 他是个聪明的家伙
That makes no sense. He's a brilliant guy.
聪明到能发现
If he's smart enough to conceive
我们安装的闭路摄像头
of technology like this...
还能用自己的技术黑进闭路系统
he's smart enough to think of something to do with it.
我抓的那个人是个送披萨的
The guy we put in jail delivered pizzas.
怎么了
So?
爱因斯坦还是职员呢
Einstein was a patent clerk.
听着你已经赢了 你抓到了
Look, you won. You got the guy who...
屏霸要想
Wait. All Screenslaver needs to do
对人进行催眠 控制人的行动
to hypnotize someone...
只需要那个人眼前有屏幕就行
is get a screen in front of their eyes.
如果那块屏幕长的不像普通的屏幕
But what if the screen doesn't look like a screen?
也许 他真的就是送披萨的
What if the pizza guy is really a pizza guy...
可他被眼睛前的屏幕
but he was controlled by the screens
控制了 然后
built into his glasses...
你真聪明
You are good.
看 机器人
Look, the robot!
起飞了
It's taking off.
我这还没有看到读数
I'm not getting a reading yet.
- 按下开火么 - 对
- Press "fire"? - Now!
加大马力
More power.
希望这能行 爸爸
Oh, I hope this works, Dad.
我想着让你一直睡到自然醒比较好
I thought it was best to just let you sleep.
你足足睡了十七个小时
Seventeen hours.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
超级好
Super.
- 成功了爸爸 - 好耶
- You got it, Dad. - Hurray!
昨晚你帮我照看小杰
I can't tell you how much I appreciate
我真不知道怎么感谢你才好 莫衣娜
you watching Jack-Jack for me, E.
行了 你的感激之情我已经心领了
Yes, I'm sure your gratitude is quite inexpressible.
下次别找我了 亲爱的
Don't ask me to do it again, darling.
我的要价可是很高的
My rates are far too high.
开玩笑的 鲍勃 你给我的任务很有趣
I am joking, Robert. I enjoyed the assignment.
小杰很聪明 我又善于引导
He is bright and I am stimulating.
我们相处的很不错
We deserve each other.
这小家伙有多种变形能力
Your child is a polymorph.
和其他孩子一样他也有很大的潜力
Like all babies, he has enormous potential.
我们已经知道有不少超人
It is not unknown for supers
有不止一种能力
to have more than one power when young...
这个小家伙 有很多种
but this little one has many.
是的呦 有很多种能力呦
Yes, you have many powers.
我能理解你睡不好觉
I understand your lack of sleep
也说不清楚话鲍勃
and coherency, Robert.
看孩子很累人
Babies can be anything,
你家的孩子也绝不是例外
and your child is no exception.
他身上可有无限的潜能 鲍勃
He has pure, unlimited potential, Robert.
昨晚他睡了之后我充满灵感的疯狂工作
He slept while I worked in a creative fever.
莫衣娜阿姨可是一整夜没睡哟
Auntie Edna stayed up all night...
就是为了让小宝贝变得漂漂亮亮的哟
making sure you look fabulous in your many forms.
这什么情况 你怎么把他放进了
What are you... You're putting him in the...
展示柜 鲍勃
In the chamber, Robert.
他也是展览的一部分
He is part of the demonstration
肯定不会有事的
and will be fine.
你的难题是要带一个
Your challenge is to manage a baby
有多种超能力的孩子
who has multiple powers...
可是没有办法控制他 对吧
and no control over them, yes?
你总结的很对
Huh. That sums it up.
我工作的时候听音乐
I often work to music
发现小杰对我听的音乐很感兴趣
and I noticed the baby responds to it as well.
特别是听 莫扎特的音乐
Specifically, Mozart.
我用了凯夫拉
I blended Kevlar
和碳炔材料来增加衣物强度
with carbyne for durability under duress...
使用棉质材料提高舒适度
and cotton for comfort.
在材料中还配备了微型的传感器
Interwoven with these fabrics are a mesh of tiny sensors...
监控他的身体情况
that monitor the baby's physical properties.
不 不天啊 他在干什么
Oh, Lord! What is he doing?
他是听到了莫扎特的音乐就分身的 鲍勃 这可没办法
Well, it's Mozart, Robert. Can you blame him?
重要的是衣服上的传感器
The important thing is that the suit and tracker...
可以预测他要分身 并且提醒你
anticipated the change and alerted you.
不 饼干
Oh, no. Cookies.
我得回去拿饼干
I gotta get cookies!
完全不需要饼干
You do not need cookies.
我昨晚已经得到了
As I learned quite painfully
沉痛的教训
last night...
如果想通过给他饼干解决问题
any solution involving cookies
最后都会让他变成恶魔宝宝
will inevitably result in the demon baby.
即将爆炸
"Combustion imminent"?
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
就是要着火了
It means fire, Robert,
不过超能装置有微型的灭火设备
for which the suit has countermeasures.
我建议你赶紧把这孩子身上的火灭掉
I suggest you extinguish the baby's flames
然后我屋里的烟雾警报器就要响了
before he trips the sprinkler system.
亲爱的 我用的是
The flame retardant
黑莓薰衣草味的阻燃剂
is blackberry lavender, darling.
见效快 可食用 而且非常美味
Effective, edible, and delicious.
大开眼界 这个还真是管用
Well, what do you know? That is useful.
虽然我的作品远远的超过了你的预期
Although, I have doubtlessly exceeded your expectations
而且只用了一个晚上的时间
for a single night's work...
这套衣服还是有几点问题
the suit and device contain
需要我们进一步讨论
a few more features we need to discuss.
谢谢你 莫衣娜 谢谢你做的一切
Thanks again, E, for everything.
我应该你给你多少钱
How much do I owe you for...
你别来这套 只要保证我是
Pish-posh, darling. Your bill will be covered by my fee...
超能先生 弹力女超人 和破冰侠
for being Mr. Incredible, Elastigirl,
在全宇宙范围里
and Frozone's exclusive designer...
唯一个超能装设计师 期限是永远永远
throughout the known universe and until the end of time.
至于照顾这个小家伙
But babysitting this one...
我分文不取 亲爱的
I do for free, darling.
我要是你
I would resist
就不会随意乱动
the temptation to stretch.
这里的气温比冰点还要低很多度
The temperature around you is well below freezing.
要是你乱动的话 胳膊会断的
Try to stretch and you'll break.
这么看来你才是真的屏霸
So, you're the Screenslaver.
也是 也不是
Yes and no.
应该是说我创造了这个形象
Let's say, I created the character
你提前录下了他要说的话
and pre-recorded the messages.
你哥哥知道吗
Does Winston know?
你问他知道我是屏霸吗 他当然不知道
That I'm the Screenslaver? Of course not.
他要是拿到了我的催眠技术
Can you imagine what Mr. Free Enterprise
为了盈利还不知道要做出什么事情
would do with my hypnosis technology?
他要做的事 难道会比你做的更坏么
Worse than what you're doing?
我是在利用技术来破除
Hey, I'm using the technology
人们对技术的迷信和过度依赖
to destroy people's trust in it.
就像我利用超人们一样
Like I'm using superheroes.
我抓住的那个人是谁
Who did I put in jail?
就是个送披萨的
Pizza delivery guy.
他的身高体重很合适
Seemed the right height, build.
他让你好好的表演了一次
He gave you a pretty good fight.
应该说是我通过他
I should say I gave you
让你好好的表演了一次
a pretty good fight through him.
一个无辜的人进了监狱
But it doesn't bother you
你也不在乎吗
that an innocent man is in jail?
他的态度很差的 披萨都凉了
Eh, he was surly and the pizza was cold.
我本来很信任你
I counted on you.
所以你才失败了
That's why you failed.
什么
What?
你为什么要信任我呢 因为我给了你摩托车
Why would you count on me? Because I built you a bike?
因为我哥哥正好会唱
Because my brother knows the words
弹力女超人的那首主题曲
to your theme song?
我们谁也不了解谁
We don't know each other.
但是你仍然可以信任我
But you can count on me anyway.
我应该信任你对吗
I am supposed to, aren't I?
因为你有奇怪的超能力
Because you have some strange abilities
还穿着闪亮的超能装
and a shiny costume...
我们这些人就应该无条件的
the rest of us are supposed to put our lives
把性命交到你双手里吗
into your gloved hands.
我父亲就是这么想的
That's what my father believed.
有强盗想闯进我们家里的时候 我妈妈想藏起来
When our home was broken into, my mother wanted to hide.
我劝我父亲去安全屋里躲躲
Begged my father to use the safe room.
但父亲坚持要给那些超人朋友打电话求助
But Father insisted they call his superhero friends.
结果死了 死的毫无意义 而且愚蠢
He died, pointlessly, stupidly...
临死前还在等着超人来拯救
waiting for heroes to save the day.
你为什么要
But why would you...
- 你哥哥 - 他就是个孩子
- Your brother... - Is a child!
他记得以前那个时代
He remembers the time
我们有父母 而且有超人
when we had parents and superheroes.
于是他就像个孩子一样 搞不清两者的区别
So, like a child, Winston conflates the two.
妈妈和爸爸丧生了 一定是因为超人离开导致的
Mommy and Daddy went away because supers went away.
我善良的父母真是傻瓜
Our sweet parents were fools
把自己的性命交到了一个超人的手里
to put their lives in anybody else's hands.
有了超人我们反而更软弱
Superheroes keep us weak.
你想要杀了我吗
Are you gonna kill me?
不
Nah.
利用你更好
Using you is better.
你可以帮助我让超人们永远不能
You're gonna help me make supers illegal...
重见天日
forever.
爸爸 爸爸
Dada. Dada.
好了吗 激光眼
Ready? Laser eyes.
停
Stop.
- 哇 - 好酷啊
- Wow! - Yeah!
- 穿上这个 - 很棒 宝贝
- Yay, Jack-Jack! - Yeah, baby!
准备好开火
And that's not all. Watch this.
小杰 激光眼准备好了么
Jack-Jack, blaster ready?
- 不会吧 - 这真是太酷了
- No way. - That is crazy cool.
我来 让我先用他开火
My turn. I get to blast him first!
- 让我来试试 我要玩嘛 - 把他给我
- Let me try. I want him. - Give him to me.
嘿 我只是展示一下
Hey, I'm just demonstrating.
在咱们家里不许让宝宝随意开火 明白吗
No firing the baby around the house, you understand?
这样玩 很可能会有危险
This is potentially dangerous...
而且我们要教他控制自己的力量 好吗
and we're trying to teach him to control his powers, okay?
先停下 看屏幕
Stop. See the screen.
他消失了 简直太厉害了
He vanished! That's really cool!
对 很好 看着屏幕
Okay, good. Use the thing.
这就是现在的读数 点一下 看到了吗
That's the current readout. Click it. See the readout?
第四维度 看到了这个形状没
Dimension four. See the shape?
这就是我们家 看到他的相对位置了吗
That's the room. See where he is in relation?
找找他在哪
So, where is he?
在那
He's... there!
好的出来吧 好吃的饼干
Okay. Come out. Num-num cookie?
耶 小杰最棒
Yeah, Jack-Jack!
真是太酷了
That's really cool.
- 喂 - 弹力女超人有麻烦了
- Hello? - Elastigirl's in trouble.
什么 出什么事了
What? What happened to her?
抱歉告诉你这个坏消息
Sorry to tell you on the phone.
来迪沃科技的船上找我
Meet me on our ship at DEVTECH.
迪沃科技的船 我十五分钟后到
The ship at DEVTECH. I'll be there in 15 minutes.
迪沃科技的船 什么事啊
What's at the ship at DEVTECH?
是鲁修斯么 我是鲍勃 何莉有麻烦了
Lucius? Bob. Helen's in trouble.
我需要你帮忙照看孩子
I need someone to watch the kids.
穿上超能服 情况可能不对
Suit up. It might get weird.
我马上去 尽快 最多一刻钟就到
I'll be there. ASAP. Fifteen tops.
你马上要去哪
Where are you going ASAP?
你最好马上回来
You better be back ASAP!
别碰那衣服
And leaving that suit.
我先走了 很快就回来
I gotta go. I'll be home soon.
鲁修斯叔叔马上到
Lucius will be here sooner.
不许在家里用小杰开炮玩
No firing the baby around the house, okay?
迪沃科技的船上到底有什么
What's at the ship at DEVTECH?
你出去干嘛还要穿超能装啊
And why are you in your Supersuit?
那是妈妈的超能装吗
Is that Mom's supersuit?
也许要用 说不好的
She may need it. You never know.
是不是发生什么事了
What's going on?
爸爸刚才说鲁修斯叔叔会过来
I don't know, but Dad called Lucius
我好像听到妈妈的名字
after getting a call about Mom...
之后他就出去了
and then left.
我以为你不会再做超人了呢
I thought you renounced superheroes.
是啊 之前的话当我没说
Yeah, well, I renounce my renunciation.
把它穿上
Put that on.
你好啊 小家伙
Hello there, little fella.
你好
Hello.
你们在家不安全
You kids aren't safe.
迪沃公司叫我来…
The Deavors sent us to take you...
不用这么多人吧
Well, isn't that redundant?
迪沃先生叫我来保护好房子
The Deavors just sent me here to guard the house.
因为孩子们不太安全
'Cause the kids aren't safe.
可能人员安排上出了点问题
I get it, managerial screw-up.
告诉文斯顿我来搞定
Tell Winston I handled it.
请问你是 超夜侠
You understand, Ms...
穿越侠女士
Voyd.
Ms. Voyd.
路上注意安全
Drive safely.
问题是 老板交代我们也要带上你
The thing is, he wants us to bring you, too.
嘿
Hey.
这样拖不了多久
That isn't gonna hold them long.
小飞 带小杰走
Dash, grab the baby!
分头去追
Spread out!
小飞
Dash!
小飞开车走
We gotta get to my car.
这是怎么回事
What? What's going on?
小家伙
Little fella!
起作用了
It worked!
超人跑车 打开窗户
Incredibile, windows down!
上车
Dive in!
这里是超人跑车 准备设置声控指令
Incredibile, set voice identification.
请大声的说出你的名字
Loudly, say your names.
- 巴小倩 - 巴小飞
- Violet Parr. - Dashiell Robert Parr.
鲁修斯
Lucius!
超人跑车 快走
Incredibile, escape!
跟我说说什么情况
Fill me in!
有一条好消息 一条坏消息 找到她了
Good news and bad news. We found her.
身体应该没有受伤
She seems physically fine
她遇到屏霸 交手一次后
but she's had an encounter with Screenslaver...
行为就有些奇怪了 她在这
and she's acting kind of strange. In here.
怎么个奇怪法
Strange how?
荷莉
Helen?
荷莉 你干嘛
Helen, what are you...
荷莉 是我
Helen, it's me.
超能跑车 路边停下
Incredibile, pull over.
我们不能去找衣夫人
We can't go to E's.
你看到他们给鲁修斯叔叔带的眼镜吗
You saw those goggles they put on Lucius.
那些超人们 他们都带眼镜
They were wearing them, too.
他们一定都是被某个人控制了
They're all under someone's control.
那个人很可能也是这样控制了妈妈
They've probably done the same to Mom.
有坏蛋在追我们
Okay. Bad guys after us.
没有妈妈 没有妈妈
No Mom, no Dad.
没有鲁修斯叔叔
No Lucius.
但是我们有超能力 还有这辆车
But we have our powers, this car...
还有什么
and... what?
超能跑车 带我们去迪沃科技大楼
Incredibile, take us to DEVTECH.
那几个孩子坐跑车逃走了
The kids have escaped in a tricked-out car,
但是我们抓住了酷冰侠
but we got Frozone.
马上把他带到正义号上来
Bring him to the ship at DEVTECH immediately.
船开走了
Aw, we missed 'em!
要是超能跑车能帮我追上那艘船就好了
Oh, I wish the Incredibile could follow that boat.
- 你干了什么 - 我不知道
- What did you do? - I don't know.
- 你到底干了什么 - 我什么都没干
- What did you do? - I didn't do anything!
我说什么这车就做什么
Wow, this car does anything I say.
现在情况可不太妙
We didn't plan this well.
怎么会 我们都到这了
What do you mean? We're here, aren't we?
对 我们是在这
Yes, we're here.
可我们需要去的是上面
We need to be up there.
嘿
Hey...
这辆超能跑车会不会正好配备了弹射座椅
What if the Incredibile has ejector seats?
慢着 什么 不要
Wait, what? No.
- 没错 - 不 别再乱说…
- Yeah, baby! - No, don't say any more...
最大功率 发射
Max power! Launch!
快点
Come on.
你们好 很高兴你们能来
Hello! Glad you could come.
欢迎来参加仪式
Welcome to the conference.
我们的主角们都去哪了
Our stars, where are they?
仪式就要开始了
The event's about to start.
他们不想抢了其他人的风头
They didn't want to upstage the others.
签字仪式开始后 他们会来的
They'll join for the signing.
欢迎登船今天我们有特别节目
Welcome, guests! You're in for a treat.
我们的正义号是整地球上最大的一艘水翼船
This ship is the largest hydrofoil on the planet.
所以大家要抓紧了
So, hold onto something...
因为我们马上就要出发了
because we're going to open her up!
我们必须找到妈妈和爸爸 你待在这
We need to find Mom and Dad. Stay here.
我出去找他们
I'm gonna search for them.
慢着 不是你看着小杰吗
Wait! Who's gonna watch Jack-Jack?
别废话了 我很快就回来
Suck it up. I won't be long.
等等…等一下
Wait. Wait, but, but wait!
听着巴小飞 爸爸妈妈有麻烦了
This is important. They are in trouble.
全靠我们了 靠我们了 你能明白吧
It's up to us. To us, understand?
赶紧好好哄哄他 安静
Keep him amused but quiet!
嘘 安静
Shh! Quiet!
小杰
Jack-Jack?
小杰 小杰
Jack-Jack? Jack-Jack!
小杰
Jack-Jack!
那几个超人不知道我们在这了
The mesmerized supers know we're here...
不过我找到了爸爸妈妈 小杰去哪了
but I found Mom and Dad... Where's Jack-Jack?
你把他丢了 我就让你干这么一件事
You lost him? I gave you one thing to do!
我有办法 有追踪器
The tracker. Use the tracker.
他在往上走
He's going up?
- 他是在电梯里 - 我们走
- He's in an elevator. - Let's go!
嘿小朋友 你爸妈在哪
Hey, little baby. Where are your parents?
各位 他们来了
And here they are, folks!
就是他们让这一切变为可能
The supers who started this whole thing.
我说过了他们会准时到达
I told you they'd be there in time.
你给他们做新面具了
Hey, did you make them new masks?
是啊 夜视功能什么的
Yeah. Night vision, et cetera...
很好看 对吧
They look good, right?
很简单的 他都会做
So simple, even he can do it.
准备直播 倒计时 三 二 一
And we're back live in three, two, one...
这是一个历史性的时刻
This is a momentous occasion.
我们今天所要完成的是
We've all managed to accomplish
当今世界上一项罕见的壮举
something extraordinarily rare in today's world.
那就是我们达成了共识
We agree on something.
要撤销一个错误的决定
We agree to undo a bad decision.
要让来自
To make sure
世界各国的少数
a few extraordinarily gifted members...
超能力拥有者在社会上得到公平对待
of the world's many countries are treated fairly.
我们还要邀请他们用自己的能力
To invite them once again to use their gifts...
造福世界
to benefit the world.
我要感谢到场的所有人
I thank all of you
你们代表了各个国家对超人的支持
for representing your nation's commitment to superheroes.
我特别要感谢塞立克大使
With special thanks to Ambassador Selick.
对 没关系 尽情鼓掌
Yeah, it's okay. Let her hear you.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you so much.
谢谢您 大使
Thank you, Ambassador,
您的支持来的最早也非常关键
for your early and very crucial support.
恐怕没有任何一个人比您更适合
I can't think of anyone more deserving than you...
第一个在国际超人协定上
to be the first signature
签上自己的名字
on the International Superhero Accord.
我签好了
There it is!
不是吧
Holy cow!
我就知道是着火了 赶快给我灭掉
I know he's on fire. Just put him out.
他们来了
They're coming.
把遥控器给他没事么
Is it okay to give him that?
难道你还有什么别的好办法
I wasn't hearing any better ideas.
不
No!
快来 小杰
Come on, Jack-Jack.
我们得走了
We have to go.
要吃饼干吗
Cookie num-num?
- 妈妈 妈妈 - 我看到他了 他跑了
- Mama, Mama. - I see him. He's getting away!
退后
Stand back.
- 丫的 - 他是去找妈妈了
- Darn it! - He's heading for Mom.
签署完成了 超人得以重见天日
It is done. The world is super again.
来合个影 来吧 大家来合影了
Group photo. Come on. Group photo, everyone.
站近一点 历史性的一刻
Squeeze in. That's it. Historic occasion.
呵呵 大家笑一笑
Everyone, smile.
开始第二步行动
Go on phase two.
多年来我们遭到压迫 如同过街老鼠般
Years of mandated hiding and silence
这使得我们超人群体对社会充满愤恨
have made us bitter.
你们现在让我们重见天日
You bring us out into the light...
只是你们缺乏自制力
only to clean up the messes
无法解决自己造成的问题
your lack of discipline creates.
你们的身体和精神都太过软弱
Your bodies and your character are weak.
你们的承诺都是空谈 你们会为此付出代价
Your promises are empty, and you will pay for it.
我们不在为你们而战
We no longer serve you.
我们只为自己而战
We serve only us.
只有强大才能生存
May the fittest survive.
哦 我们
Well, we, um...
看来直播出现了一些情况
Some very alarming moments there...
可能是有些技术问题
before the, uh, technical difficulties.
请不要走开
Please bear with us.
设呢么
What?
求救 求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
等一下 让他说完
Hold! Let him talk.
有超人闯进来占领了驾驶舱 重复一遍
Superheroes have forcibly taken the bridge. Repeat.
重复一遍
Now.
再转
A little further.
再转 停下
Little further. Stop.
什么情况 一个宝宝
What the... A baby?
爸爸妈妈 鲁修斯叔叔
Mom and Dad. Uncle Lucius?
- 妈妈 妈妈 - 小杰 不要
- My mama. - Jack-Jack, no!
有超能力的宝宝
A super baby?
不不不不不
No, no, no!
快把他放下
Put him down!
- 抓住她 - 不!
- Grab her! - No!
抱着小杰
Hold Jack-Jack.
不
No!
嗨 是我
Hey, it's me!
上次我也是这么说的
Yeah, that's what I thought last time.
孩子们 你们怎么
Kids, what are you...
过来救我们了
You came for us?
别生我们的气
Don't be mad.
啊 好孩子 我怎么可能生气
Oh, sweetie, how could I be mad?
我是很骄傲
I'm proud.
抱歉 我不是想打扰你们温馨的团聚
Not to break up a tender moment,
不过我们这是在哪
but where are we?
这是迪沃科技的船吗
Is this DEVTECH's ship?
是伊芙琳那个家伙创造了屏霸
Evelyn Deavor controls the Screenslaver...
而且刚才她还控制了我们
and until a second ago, us.
船员在哪
Where's the crew?
碰撞即将发生 请调整航线
Collision detected. Correct course.
那是我干的么
Uh-oh. Did I do that?
妈妈 你的超能服 换上这个
Mom, the suit? Try this.
第三步 现在执行第三步
Phase Three. Go on Phase Three!
孩子们怎么在这 你难道没去我家
Why are the kids here? You didn't go to the house?
我去了你家
I went to the house.
你们没逃走吗 你们怎么没逃走
You didn't escape? How did you not escape?
嘿 我们刚救了你
Hey! We just saved you!
逃走 谁在逃走
Escape? Escape from who?
就是他们
Those guys!
小杰居然有超能力了
What the...? Jack-Jack has powers?
当然了 打完了再跟你说
We know. Fight now, talk later.
小杰
Jack-Jack.
激光眼
Laser eyes!
快跟我来 温斯顿
Come with me, Winston.
- 我的头好晕啊 - 你在这很安全
- Did I faint? - You'll be safe here.
安全 这里怎么了
Safe? Safe from what?
那些外交官们呢 超…超人呢
Where are the diplomats? The supers?
还在催眠呢
Still hypnotized.
你都干了些什么
What have you done?
伊芙琳逃走了
Evelyn, she's escaping.
那就…快去追她啊
Well, go after her.
完成你的任务
Finish your mission.
我不能就这么走了 孩子怎么办
I can't just go! What about the kids?
- 小杰呢 谁来照顾 - 妈
- Jack-Jack, who's gonna... - Mom!
快去 我们能搞定的
Go. We've got this.
穿越侠 你跟我来
Voyd, come with me.
我去关闭发动机
I'll go shut down the engine.
我去船头想办法让船减速
I'll try to slow the ship from the bow.
慢着 有个人不见了 那个挤压东西的家伙去哪了
Wait, someone's missing. Where's the crusher guy?
系上安全带 快
Strap in now!
我这是为了你好
It's for your own good.
不
No!
这才是
This is.
- 我们太迟了 - 送我上飞机
- We're too late. - Get me up to the jet.
嘿 这是你干的 你能把这些复原吗
Hey, you did this. Can you undo it?
你想让我反碾压一下吗
You want me to un-crush?
怎么 没人这么要求过我啊
What? No one's ever asked for that?
没有 反碾压太傻了 干嘛要反碾压
No. To un-crush is silly. Why un-crush?
我要进引擎室
To get into the engine room.
噢 算了 已经没有时间了
Oh, forget it. We don't have enough time.
那你能反打一下左勾拳吗
What if I said to un-punch someone?
这根本没法打
What do you do?
欢迎登机 弹力女超人
Welcome aboard, Elastigirl.
虽然我们现在
Although we haven't yet reached
还没有达到巡航高度
our cruising altitude...
你可以在机舱内自由活动
feel free to roam about the cabin.
或者你放松
Or just relax...
让机舱在你身边翻滚
and let the cabin roam about you.
我进不了引擎室
I can't get to the engine room!
我们总得想出个办法
We gotta do something!
因为船已经不能减速了
Because trying to slow it down ain't working.
那我们让船转向呢
Hey! What about turning the boat?
船的方向杆已经毁掉了
The steering's been destroyed!
- 小飞是说 从外面转弯 - 是的
- Dash means from the outside! - Yeah!
要折断水翼
If we break off one of the foils
再使劲转动船舵
and turn the rudder...
正义号就不会撞上岸边了
we can veer the ship away from the city!
这办法也许有用
That might work.
我去推船头 你去推船尾
I'll turn the front, you turn the rear.
转动船舵 那可是在水下
Using the rudder? That's underwater.
我又怎么才能
How am I supposed to get...
好吧 跟我过来孩子们
All right. Come on, kids.
爸爸 我知道这办法能成功
Dad, I know this is going to work.
但是万一不成功 船撞上岸边了
But if it doesn't, and we crash...
我的防护罩比船体更坚固
my shields are probably better protection than the ship.
我应该留在这 保护好小杰
I should stay here. With Jack-Jack.
真不愧是我女儿
That's my girl.
记住了 鲍勃 我们两个都往右转
Remember, Bob, we're both turning right!
我还挺难过的
You know what's sad?
若不是不是因为你的理想信念
If it weren't for your core beliefs...
我们也许还会成为好朋友
I think we could have been good friends.
至少我还有…
At least...
我还有理想
I have core beliefs.
有突发新闻
We have breaking news...
虽然我们还没有收到相应的视频信号
While there is still no radio contact,
正义号已经转向
the ship has changed direction...
用最快的速度朝着
and is heading towards land
城市海岸行驶了
at a high rate of speed.
小飞
So, Dash...
我 现在下去找船舵
I am going to the rudder.
轮船一旦转向 你就按下按钮 把我拉上来
Once I turn the ship, you hit the pull up button.
- 好的 爸爸 - 现在放我下去
- Okay, Dad. - Now lower me down...
你们超人的好名声 已经毁了
The reputations of superheroes are ruined.
你们永远不能再合法化了
You will never become legal. Ever.
永远么
Never?
永远
No.
- 真的吗 - 没错
- Ever? - No.
连一点点机会都没有么
Not even a little smidgee-widgee?
你缺氧了啊
Oh, hypoxia.
一旦你的氧气不足
When you don't have enough oxygen,
世界就显得特别的傻
things seem really silly.
世界变的越来越傻
Things get sillier
然后你就
and sillier and then you die.
我还不想死 不想死
I don't wanna die.
说真的 没人想死
Ah, nobody does.
不过
Really.
蠢死也不错
Not such a bad way to go.
所有人 请你们马上到船尾去
Everyone, we need to get to the back of the ship.
所有超人 保护好大使
All supers, protect your ambassadors!
走这边
Follow.
爸爸下去的时间太长了
Dad's been underwater for too long.
我得把他拉下来
We gotta pull him up.
等等 现在还太早
Wait. It's too soon.
我要按下按钮了
I'm gonna press the button!
还不行
Not yet!
船头动了 成功了
It's turning. It's working.
- 快 - 小飞 快按
- Now! - Dash, now!
快变成降落伞
Save yourself. Make a chute.
快变 快变 快变
Make a chute. Make a chute.
变成降落伞
Make a chute!
荷莉 站稳了
Helen! Brace yourselves!
要撞上了
Crash positions!
我居然没有看到小杰的第一种超能力
I missed Jack-Jack's first power?
其实你已经错过了十七种了
Actually, you missed the first 17.
就算你出手救了我 也不能证明你是对的
The fact that you saved me doesn't make you right.
但至少现在你还活着
But it does make you alive.
对此我也十分感谢
And I'm grateful for that.
我很遗憾 不过她要进监狱了
I'm sorry, but she'll go to prison.
我也很遗憾 她那么有钱
Well, I'm sorry she's rich
大概费不了多大的劲就能出狱了吧
and will probably get no more than a slap on the wrist.
我想说 巴小倩 我很喜欢你
First of all, Violet, I like you.
还有 谁知道未来还会发生什么
And who knows what the future may bring...
但是我对你们大家都有很好的预感
but I have a good feeling about all of you.
嗯哼 好的预感
Hmm. Good feeling.
谁知道将来会怎么样
Should we be worried?
你们站下一班岗 我去休息了
You guys got the next shift. I'm beat. Oh!
我看到了你刚才的表现 太出色了
I saw what you did back there. That was incredible!
我没想着用双关语来着
No pun intended.
抱歉我当时揍了你
Sorry I had to punch you.
真棒 去兜风咯
Yeah, baby! My sweet ride!
鉴于拥有超能力的超人群体
And in recognition of the extraordinary service
为社会所做出的杰出贡献
they have demonstrated...
我宣布 现在正式恢复超人和超能力的
the legal status of superheroes
合法地位
is hereby restored.
你还不认识我 是这样吗
You don't know me, do you?
我不认识你
No, I don't...
慢着
Wait.
你就是餐厅里呛水的那个
Are you the girl with the water?
我叫巴小倩
I'm Violet Parr.
- 我叫托尼 - 好吧
- I'm Tony. - Okay.
你分成几个组之类的…
You split up into separate groups and stuff...
托尼 这是我妈妈
Tony, this is my mom.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
- 这是我爸爸 - 你好 我们见过
- This is my dad. - Oh, we've met.
真是很尴尬
And this is embarrassing.
我很帅气吧
Charmed, I'm sure.
是我弟弟 小飞
My little brother, Dash.
后面的小朋友 是我弟弟小杰
And the baby is Jack-Jack.
我已经努力劝说他们只来一个人就行了
I tried to limit it to one parent.
我们正好都要去看电影 托尼 不用在意
We're all going to a movie, too, Tony. Don't mind us.
我们会远远的
We'll be sitting
坐在电影院的另一边
on the other side of the theater.
不会打扰你们的
Not watching you.
他是说着玩的
He's kidding.
他们只是开车送我们到电影院门口
They are only dropping us off at the theater.
接下来他们还有别的事要忙呢
They have other things to do.
看来你们家人关系很好啊
So, you guys are close, I guess.
- 是的 是这样 - 也许你能加入我们大家一起更亲密呢
- Yeah, I guess. - We can get closer.
鲍勃
Bob.
停车 让我们出去
Stop! Let us out!
我要大份爆米花 小份汽水
Here, large popcorn, small soda.
买中间位置 最好倒数第八排
Save me a seat, center, about eight rows back.
片头广告结束之前我就回来
I'll be back before the previews are over.